<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aditya Jeevannavar</title>
    <description>I conduct bioinformatics research as my dayjob and continue to stare at my laptop screen writing and tinkering on side-projects the rest of the day.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 17:15:58 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 17:15:58 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>

    
      <item>
        <title>Massive Manhunt for MLM Marauders Made Public</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;massive-manhunt-for-mlm-marauders-made-public&quot;&gt;Massive Manhunt for MLM Marauders Made Public&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;its-not-a-ponzi-scheme-ponzi-the-third-fraud-expert&quot;&gt;It’s not a Ponzi scheme: Ponzi, the Third (Fraud Expert)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bhubaneshwar, May 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Citizens all over the country have been receiving calls, messages, emails, and letters asking every reader to donate to charities like “Save the children” or “Save the Indigenous communities” or “Save the affected”. CBI Bhubaneshwar has cracked into the headquarters of one such “charity” NGO conducting their business out of an abandoned building in the Rokat neighbourhood. “The headquarters had no certified community workers. It was run entirely by marketing enthusiasts,” said CBI Inspector Reddy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A team of cross-department government officials is now investigating and auditing the financials of the NGO which ran the “Save the children” campaign. Many such NGOs and campaigns are thought to be linked and are rumoured to be equally as dubious. The manhunt to find them all continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Independent investigative journalists have found that there are no children that have been saved and that all the images on their website, posters, and social media pages were procured from a Swedish photographer on tour in urban Mumbai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We don’t have any assets or any workforce,” said the whistleblower who brought the “charity” to the attention of the CBI. “We just have volunteers. Initially we wanted to raise some money to start the project. So, we went around to the local colleges with some stock images on some posters and got a bunch of volunteers. But slowly it became clear that it was way way (sic) easier to just recruit volunteers than actually raise money.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most volunteers joined the NGO in order to have the satisfaction of having worked for the well-being of the society at large. Most volunteers, though, were extremely bad at raising money. In a few months, the official policy was altered so that each volunteer had to either raise ₹50k or 50 new volunteers each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We wanted to do good,” continued the whistleblower. “But the money and the volunteers kept pouring in and we didn’t even have to do anything. The team just kept on thinking of more ways to raise money than to actually use the money for anything. That is when it all went wrong.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initial reports of the NGO team’s arrests claimed it all to be a pyramid scheme. The NGO chairman has since claimed that it is a false accusation and has tried to clear it. “No, it is not a pyramid scheme,” said the chairman. “We don’t give any of the money to the early volunteers. The volunteers join in because they want to. They want to feel that they are contributing to society. That experience. That is what we are offering to the people. The money is just a by-product.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fraud experts are conflicted in whether this is a pyramid scheme, a Ponzi scheme, or neither. With Multi-Level Marketing being a legal and well-accepted business model, proving fraud appears even more challenging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the government has seen to it that the network of volunteers used by the now dissolved NGOs does not go to waste and that the volunteers are instead used to raise funds for PM CARES. PMO has also clarified that expenditure of funds raised this way will not be made public either.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/volunteering-mlm/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/volunteering-mlm/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sting Operation of Forward Factory faces backlash</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;sting-operation-of-forward-factory-faces-backlash&quot;&gt;Sting Operation of Forward Factory faces backlash&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pahlaj-nihalani-named-chairman-of-the-newly-formed-central-board-of-forward-certification&quot;&gt;Pahlaj Nihalani named Chairman of the newly formed Central Board of Forward Certification&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gandhinagar, May 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: A sting operation by &lt;a href=&quot;https://thegrimes.substack.com&quot;&gt;The Hindustan Grimes&lt;/a&gt; in association with CID Gujarat has revealed operations of the BJP IT Cell’s West Wing (WW). The covert operation, led by our very own Momo, began in early January this year. There is speculation that The Grimes was started as a front for the operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The IT Cell always reached me through the grapevine, but finding them directly took a lot of effort,” said a visibly ruffled Momo. “It began with a lot of hanging around family groups and neighbourhood uncles’ groups. That yielded only forwards. Then, we started setting our own traps. One of my avatars went in so deep, it got the forwards before they were even labelled forwards.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Finally, we found one of their creatives’ real facebook account,” Momo continued. “We made up an advertising account and asked FB for his address so we could sell him banyans and they just gave it to us. That is when the whole operation went sour.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that the IT Cell operative that the operation found was quite normal and did not need to be especially tortured to speak about the Cell’s operations. She was quite friendly and spoke openly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The WW IT Cell, internally known as Forward Factory, primarily consists of struggling writers who never made it in mainstream writing. “There is no long form reading audience that’ll connect with our Indian stories,” she said. “And Bollywood doesn’t like writers getting creative, so this is the only choice. It even pays well.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IT Cell writers add that they don’t have faith in the conventional news agencies. One, they don’t have the money, and the ones’ that do have money shouldn’t be called news agencies anyway. Two, they write just about anything. Three, you are forced to write about celebrities or politicians all the time. “At least we don’t say it’s all true and sign our names under it,” said an anonymous writer, who goes by @shambiguity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“FF takes care of us,” said @mrpatel, another writer. “The IT Cells up north are generally okay. But some of the Cells in the fringes are almost prison cells and are run like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-50883161&quot;&gt;Chinese card factories&lt;/a&gt;. Those imprisoned indentured slave-like writers don’t even get EPFO.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sting operation also revealed that multiple attempts at unionisation of the writers have been crushed, sometimes with the involvement of police officers. Suspected officers have been put on paid suspension. It is believed that the PM appreciates IT Cells’ growth and views them as successes of Aatmanirbharata and Make in India programs, but is also in talks with Amazon for their expertise. “No one crushes unionisation attempts and exploits workers like they do. Every capitalist could learn a thing or two from Amazon,” said Dr. Subramanian Swamy, MP and former professor of economics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMO has said that this was one of the avenues for creating employment for the youth in the country. The IT Cells’ funding was accounted for in the union budget. Upon enquiry about why this was not revealed earlier, the PMO confessed to a large backlog of announcements. “We have some announcements pending since last December,” said the PMO reply. “We’ve not even got to the announcements about placing orders for vaccines for 18-44! Oh wait! We still have to place the orders first.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Television news broadcasters however have ignored the sting operation in favour of the failed return attempts of COVID19, IPL, and Sushant Singh Rajput.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/forward-factory/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/forward-factory/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Momo and Eggsy's Excellent Adventure</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;momo-and-eggsys-excellent-adventure&quot;&gt;Momo and Eggsy’s Excellent Adventure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;20-of-bankruptcy-cases-result-from-teenagers-failing-to-cancel-subscription-before-free-trial-ends&quot;&gt;20% of bankruptcy cases result from teenagers failing to cancel subscription before free trial ends&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moodabidri, May 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Zoom Inc., which provides seamless communication services across space, has announced that it will soon add to its premium features list seamless communication across time as well^. The Grimes, due to its eminence as a public media body, was given exclusive early access. As a result, we interviewed myriad famous thinkers and historical figures from the previous century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Presented below is a brief excerpt of the group interview.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The past 18 months have been terrible for the world. A viral pandemic, COVID19, has spread across the world and killed millions of people. Do you have advice for the people of your future?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stalin: “This is no tragedy. A single death is a tragedy, a million deaths is a statistic. Get over it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But it brought the world to a standstill. Everyone was locked down, trying to save others from getting infected. &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/LHhbdXCzt_A&quot;&gt;We live in a society&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thatcher: “There is no such thing as a society! The problem with socialism is that you eventually run out of other peoples’ money.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We know that the world leaders, Trump, Putin, Johnson, Modi, all made mistakes. But, you’re saying locking down was a mistake?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thatcher: “Of course. They are all men. I’ve always said, in politics, if you want anything said, ask a man. If you want anything done, ask a woman.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Einstein: “Yes. Yes. This is all a game. God doesn’t play dice with the world. These are culling techniques honed over millennia.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MLK, Jr.: “Truth. We are not makers of history; we are made by history.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I really don’t think you are grasping the severity of the damage done here. Millions of people have died.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Einstein: “This reminds me of what Oppenheimer keeps saying at the university cafeteria: ‘Now I am become Death, the destroyer of worlds.’ All that radiation he works with has gotten to his head. Is the whole world irradiated perhaps?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will not answer that. But anyway, there is some hope. Numerous vaccines have been made to battle the virus…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Armstrong: “That’s one small step for man, one giant leap for mankind.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes. The vaccines will save us. If only we could produce enough of them in time for it to matter.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gandhi: “No. No. This is too much technology. We need to go back to our roots. In a gentle way, we can shake the world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oh! What do you suggest we do then?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ali (interrupting Gandhi): “Float like a butterfly. Sting like a bee. The virus can’t hit what it can’t see.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandela: “No. No. Education. Education is the most powerful weapon we can use to change the world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stalin: “Really, Mr. Mandela? Education is a weapon, yes, but its effects depend on who holds it in his hands and at whom it is aimed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the same time, we are spending thousands of crores on a new Parliament building. Do you think that’s also one small step for the Indian man?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharma: “Saare jahan se acchha. Astronauts go to space and try to find their country and can’t manage finding them. With the Vista, we Indians will be able to appreciate Hindustan even more.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But don’t you think India’s PM is cheating the Indian people by investing money into this project, rather than ramp up vaccine production? Isn’t that criminal?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nixon: I am not a crook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clinton: I did not have sexual relations with that woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of them together: Oh, that wasn’t directed at me. Sorry. Force of habit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Many are claiming this is a making of the Chinese. Is this not racism?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Churchill: “This is not a riddle, wrapped in a mystery, inside an enigma. I can see how it can be the Chinese’s doing. We shall fight them on the beaches. We shall never surrender Hong Kong.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gandhi: “No. Inciting violence is not the right way. An eye for an eye will make the whole world blind.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So you do believe that the Chinese did it. You are racist.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ford: “Racism? What racism? That ended long ago. Any customer of mine can have a car painted any colour that he wants so long as it is black.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MLK, Jr.: “I have a dream, a dream where I can drive a black car.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ford: “You can do that in a Ford Model T.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MLK, Jr.: “Oh alright then.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The interview soon spiralled into discussions of racism, socialism, governance, and war. In the interest of censorship, the transcript of the interview is terminated here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;^As far back as the 1950s, for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Quotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Quotes/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Popular feminist spokesperson, May May, releases new book on Objectification of Women</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;popular-feminist-spokesperson-may-may-releases-new-book-on-objectification-of-women&quot;&gt;Popular Feminist Spokesperson, May May, Releases New Book on Objectification of Women&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;objectification-and-objectophilia-offends-the-objectifiers-the-objectified-and-the-objectophiliacs-alike&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objectification and Objectophilia&lt;/strong&gt; offends the objectifiers, the objectified, and the objectophiliacs alike.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bangalore, April 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Dr. May May, during a special session of the Bangalore Literature Festival, was thrown a Mochi size 6 casual khaki loafer at when she mentioned that “while objectophiliacs are mentally deranged, their derangement is not a feminist issue.” Critics have called her a hypocrite and a self-involved snob for publishing a whole book about the “non-issue”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. May defines objectophilia as &lt;em&gt;a sexual and/or romantic attraction toward inanimate objects&lt;/em&gt; and objectification as &lt;em&gt;degrading someone to the status of a mere object&lt;/em&gt;. “You can see where some people get confused,” says Dr. May. “Objectophiliacs and women objectifiers have different kinds of illnesses.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    If he has a thing for her, fine.&lt;br /&gt;
    If he has a thing for it, trouble.&lt;br /&gt;
    If she is the thing, call the police and/or twitter-police.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Nariman “Nari” Dealer took offence on behalf of all women in the country and called for a twitter ban on Dr. May going against feminism. Nari Dealer questioned Dr. May’s loyalty to feminism. He tweeted, “Women objectification is no joke. Dr. May is a thing of the past. She’s wrong. #cancelmaymay”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popular objectophiliac and part-time general scholar on the prime time television news circuit, Ms. Samanpreet Kaur defended people of her affliction with an online statement: “… before, it was all men are equal. Now, we have changed the paradigm to all humans are equal. We just want to nudge the public narrative a bit further. Everything is equal.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Objectophiliacs Anonymous took out a walking march in front of the Lit Fest’s premises on the morning after the special session with Dr. May. They demonstrated the truth of their love by carrying their object loves in the march. While the people of small affinities carried their wares at the front of the march, others with more elaborate lovers like refrigerators and washing machines had to be offered gatorades and physical help to cross the slightly slopy parking lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some unfortunate objectophiliacs who were married to buildings like the Eiffel tower were unable to obtain permissions to bring their lovers on the Inner Ring Road and hence had to participate with life-sized cut-outs. “God created humans. Humans created buildings. Call me a stickler for the transitive property, but I can only love things if I know where they came from,” said an Eiffel tower lover.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Objectophilia-and-Feminism/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Objectophilia-and-Feminism/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Govt. says war on COVID too hard. Will target Vertigo instead</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;govt-says-war-on-covid-too-hard-will-target-vertigo-instead&quot;&gt;Govt. says war on COVID too hard. Will target Vertigo instead.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;diseasevertigo-trends-1-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;#Disease?Vertigo trends #1 Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Delhi, April 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: In a surprising press conference, Union Health Minister Dr. Harsh Vardhan declared that the war on COVID19 was too hard and that it was futile. They have decided to regroup and convalesce and then wage war on vertigo instead. “We don’t think we’ll win. We’re just losing too many of our people,” said the Minister for Health. “So, we decided to get back to the drawing board and set new targets. There’s no point crying over unassailable targets.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ve talked to the WHO and all the major foreign health departments. They’re all on board,” said Minister of State for Health, Mr. Ashwini Kumar Choubey. “We’ve organised the forces—health workers, doctors, slogan writers, and social media experts. Everything’s set. We’ll completely annihilate vertigo.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitterati were concerned how WHO or any other organisation was behind this, but their concerns were soon alleviated. It has come to fore that China is busy with the business in the South China Sea and has loosened the grip on WHO. Also, the whole idea of shifting targets is believed to have come from the US Dept. of Biological Warfare Director and Vietnam War Veteran, General J. Rambo. Gen. Rambo is said to have convinced the international intelligence communities to convince the health departments that this is the best choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon being asked about why vertigo was being set as the new target, Dr. Vardhan said, “It’s very simple really. The previous management, us mostly, set unachievable targets and that has brought down the morale of the team very very down (sic). We feel like setting this small target will help raise the morale again.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then again, Vertigo, simple as it is,” he continued, “hasn’t been worked on by enough smart minds, because, well, they’ve never been needed to. But now, we can beat it and take the moral win. We’ll all go home after and have some real cause for cheer. Anyway, we’ve given it a few decades’ head start. Now, we’ll just knock on its door, and when it opens the door, carpet-bomb it thoroughly.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we asked what would happen if the coronavirus mutates and makes people get vertigo, the Dr. Vardhan was visibly flummoxed. After a few quick words with his team, the minister appeared dismayed and said softly, “oh no. It will do that, won’t it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No word since has been heard from the Health Ministry, but another change of target is expected by Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/COVID-Fight-Too-Tough/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/COVID-Fight-Too-Tough/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PM Modi claims Kumbh Mela was a Secret Masterstroke</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;pm-modi-claims-kumbh-mela-was-a-secret-masterstroke&quot;&gt;PM Modi claims Kumbh Mela was a Secret Masterstroke&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;iits-demand-expedited-vaccines-for-students-get-rejected-summarily-iit-gandhinagar-vaccinates-students-anyway&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;IITs demand expedited vaccines for students. Get rejected summarily. IIT Gandhinagar vaccinates students anyway.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Siliguri, April 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: At a campaign rally for the ongoing West Bengal Legislative Assembly election, speaking in his classic campaign rhetoric, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said, “all the large gatherings at the Kumbh Mela were not only planned, but also organised in such a way as to maximize herd immunity. Not only that, even the large gatherings at our campaign rallies in the state have been scientifically organised.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister is believed to have grown weary of the Principal Scientific Adviser’s principles and advice, and is therefore heeding to other sources unknown to the public. The Prime Minister’s Office has said, “Oh yeah, we made many mistakes. We gave vaccines to retirees sitting at home instead of poor daily wagers who’re dying due to the curfews and lockdowns. Our website doesn’t work properly and cannot handle lakhs of people logging on at once. But, this. &lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt; is not a mistake.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While under fire for vaccine shortages, the government has decided to fast track approvals for COVID-19 vaccines that have been granted emergency use authorisation by foreign drug regulators. “Baba Ramdev asked me to push his vaccine through, but I said no,” said PM Modi. “I still believe in our CDSCO^ and NEGVAC^.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opposition claims that this is an old habit of Mr. Modi. “He takes a bad situation and acts like it was a brilliant plan all along. He’ll just come out, look at an enormous disaster, and say it is all alright with a straight face. He’s just faking it,” said INC spokesperson, Abhishek Singhvi, and grumbled, “&lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; somehow making it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Modi has been known to sometimes fudge the truth and other times butcher it completely. For example, he claimed that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://factsmodified.factchecker.in/august-15-2018/&quot;&gt;export of honey&lt;/a&gt; had doubled in 2018 while it had only increased 17% year-on-year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the Prime Minister lying left and right, it makes one wonder if the 2016 demonetization really happened or not. (It definitely did.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;^CDSCO = Cetral Drugs Standard Control Organization, NEGVAC = National Expert Group on Vaccine Administration for COVID-19&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Kumbh-Mela-Fiasco/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Kumbh-Mela-Fiasco/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Walmart procures AI-powered headphones that turns all speech polite</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;walmart-procures-ai-powered-headphones-that-turns-all-speech-polite&quot;&gt;Walmart procures AI-powered headphones that turns all speech polite&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ibm-watson-declares-ai-not-a-bubble&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;IBM Watson declares AI not a bubble&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silicon Valley, April 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Simons Say Please Inc., one of thousands in the new AI-powered start-up scene, has launched their first product, the BoomerRemover. BoomerRemover is an AI-powered wireless pair of headphones that modifies the voices the wearer hears^ to make it polite. The speaker’s voice’s texture, pronunciation, accent, and other identifying qualities remain the same, but the tone of voice used is converted to a polite one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, it won’t seem like you are always speaking to Siri or Alexa. It’s not monotonous &lt;em&gt;that way&lt;/em&gt;,” said Mr. Tim Simon, CTO of Simons Say Please. “It’s like a person standing in front of you and shouting ‘WHAT THE FUCK IS WRONG WITH YOU? THERE IS NOT ENOUGH CHEESE ON THIS!’, but all you hear is ‘Can you please add a bit more cheese on this?’ in their own calm voice.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is going to revolutionize the service industry,” said Mr. Tom Simon, CEO of Simons Say Please. “Walmart has seen the potential in BoomerRemover and bought out the first lot. This is sure to reduce their store employees’ stress levels immediately.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boomers For Fairness (BFF(s)), a support group for hassled and baffled boomers, has warned Walmart of protests in front of their stores. BFFs believe that the “AI” headphones are powered by 5G and that they cause imbalances in their body’s energy and lead to spread of infectious diseases. “Bringing out such things in the middle of a pandemic is just plain insensitive,” said a mask-on-the-chin BFF, Karen Wachowski.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several questions have been raised about Walmart procuring BoomerRemovers, primary of which is “Why?” Walmart Press Secretary, Ms. Pavitra Suman, said in an interview, “we care about our employees. It is better to give them the protection of BoomerRemover than to risk them ending up with PTSD due to the savage customers. Working at the frontline entails a lot of pressure and stress, especially when the customers are rude and refuse to obey guidelines.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Walmart’s long time management consultants, McKinsey &amp;amp; Co., ceased services for the retail corporation. “They decided that procuring $400 headphones for everyone is cheaper than paying for their therapy. But, do you know what is even cheaper than that? Not paying for therapy at all. You just hire new minimum wagers to replace the weak ones,” said a McKinsey associate formerly consulting the retailer who wished to remain anonymous, for obvious reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms. Casandra Wong, a Walmart store employee at the Fresno facililty said, “before, I used to hate going to work. But now, with these headphones, I feel good. It really feels like the company cares about us. Now, if only they could pay us slightly more than minimum wage so I can afford to buy my dog some treats.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;^Not applicable to internal monologues and ghostly heart-to-hearts&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/BoomerRemover-AI-Headphones/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/BoomerRemover-AI-Headphones/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Censor Board and RSS approve indigenous superhero for the Indian audience</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;censor-board-and-rss-approve-indigenous-superhero-for-the-indian-audience&quot;&gt;Censor Board and RSS Approve Indigenous Superhero for the Indian Audience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;anurag-kashyap-removed-from-project-after-first-draft-of-script-leaks&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anurag Kashyap removed from project after first draft of script leaks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prayagraj, April 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: In a press release at the Kumbh Mela event yesterday, producer and writer, Mr. Vikram Betal, announced the making of a new blockbuster movie building the origin of HanuMan and his adventurous attempt at saving Ayodhya from ruin. The live action movies are set in modern day Ayodhya with futuristic technology and ancient wisdom. The superhero based on the mythological character of the same name will be the star in a movie trilogy (to be released in Hindi as well as 8 other regional languages) and an animated television series for kids. A short teaser was also unveiled at the press meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hanuman is a character epitomising strength (physical and of-character), morals, and devotion to a cause. He works tirelessly toward protecting all that he believes sacred,” says Mr. Valmiki, co-writer of the movie. “There have been many screen adaptations of Hanuman’s story but they all tell the same stories in the same millennia old setting. We are expending the creative effort of setting Hanuman in the 21st century.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pre-production for the first movie has completed and production has just begun. It is set to introduce the ancient secret society of Hanumen and their current leader, the Hanuman. “This is a classic origin story movie that establishes who our protagonist is and how he is struggling with his devotion to saving humans and saving morals,” said Mr. Valmiki. “The Ministry of Propaganda approached us last week and asked if we could set the premise as, ‘Hanuman can save only one at a time, but you, mortal human, can follow safety guidelines and save hundreds.’ We’ve not decided what to do. An apprentice of mine came up with the idea of making an Animatrix-esque short film. So maybe we’ll do that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Film critics have already show appreciation for the teaser and in the short teaser of the movie, we see the titular character, Shiv Kumar, turn into Hanuman by ripping the skin flap on his chest open and chanting “Jai Shri Ram”. The writers revealed that they initially considered the transformation act too gory and wanted Shiv to beat his chest with his fists instead. But further discussions established this too close to Tarzan for comfort and the peoples’ self-deprecating humour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;American and Japanese superheroes begin their stories in comic books and then they are adapted for motion picture. When asked about this, producer Mr. Betal said, “No, we’re not doing comic books. One, people don’t read comic books. Two, people don’t buy comic books. Three, people can’t afford comic books, at least the people who we think will be interested in our comic books. Anyway, we have ancient stories of the Hanuman in spoken and written word. I don’t think making a graphic novel first is necessary.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hanuman Trilogy is expected to hit theatres over the next three years and is also expected to boggle the minds of both critics and audiences. There are plans to introduce side-kicks like Jatayu, Angad, and Sugreev; whether they will be included in the trilogy itself or be part of a more expansive superhero universe is not known at the moment. Talks of a spin-off animated television show titled &lt;em&gt;Adolescent Avatars Go!&lt;/em&gt;, consisting of avatars of Vishnu and Shiva, have also surfaced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indigenous creativity appears to be approaching every screen near you soon, but it might be a bit too early to tell you that you wouldn’t be in the wrong to have high hopes, this time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Hanuman-Superhero-Indigenaire/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Hanuman-Superhero-Indigenaire/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>IITM Dean promotes Grammarly. Make In India Dept. demands probe.</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;iitm-dean-promotes-grammarly-make-in-india-dept-demands-probe&quot;&gt;IITM Dean Promotes Grammarly. ‘Make In India’ Dept. Demands Probe.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;grammarly-to-bring-grammar-nazism-to-hindi-kannada-tamil-soon&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grammarly to bring Grammar Nazism to Hindi, Kannada, Tamil soon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chennai, April 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: After yet another exasperating farrago of demonstrably incoherent emails hit Indian Institute of Technology Madras’ Dean of Academic Courses this mid-semester, the dean broke. In an institute-wide announcement, the dean said, “I am fed up of all of you, students, faculty, and staff. Grasping enough knowledge of the English language to write a concise univocal email is a basic requirement. Get good. Please.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dean claims that since his appointment to the post three months ago, he has had to discontinue his research activities indefinitely due to the overwhelming administrative work. He is also believed to have started medications for hypertension last month. “It is a very tense and belabouring position. It is only aggravated by the incomprehensible emails that we receive every day,” said the new secretary to the dean over an email exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The institute-wide announcement also contained the dean’s plea for all members of the institute to download Grammarly extensions onto their web browsers and Grammarly Keyboard onto their mobile devices. In a leaked confidential email to the teaching staff, the dean is said to have asked them to promote Grammarly usage in their classwork and assignments/reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following instructions, a chemistry department professor asked students in his data structures class to use Grammarly via a detailed post on the class’ Moodle forum. The forum post was deleted an hour later after 42 of his 44 students replied to the message with “no u”. In a more recent email in the confidential thread, the dean has emphasised on the professors using Grammarly first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dean is also in talks with the Assistant Registrar in charge of tenders and procurement for buying institute-wide premium memberships, for students, faculty, and staff. The transaction may cost the institute an additional two crore rupees in spending every year. Additional Secretaries in the Ministry of Education are peeved and have sent a strongly worded letter to the institute administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an interview with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.t5eiitm.org/author/eggsy/&quot;&gt;T5E&lt;/a&gt;, the institute’s student media body, the students’ general secretary asked: “Is he even allowed to promote private companies and products? Aren’t all govt. officials banned from doing that?” The T5E correspondent reportedly retorted with “maybe you should cut back on watching all that American television.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the Ministry of Commerce’s Make in India department is promoting young Indian entrepreneurs to come up with indigenous solutions to the (un)grammatical problems. Entrepreneurs have been asked not to worry about issues such as intellectual property rights.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Grammarly/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Grammarly/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rekha Arya: A Profile of an Animal Welfare Activist</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;rekha-arya-a-profile-of-an-animal-welfare-activist&quot;&gt;Rekha Arya: A Profile of an Animal Welfare Activist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samarkand, April 2021:&lt;/strong&gt; Rekha Arya is the current Minister of Women and Child Welfare, Government of Uttarakhand and member of the Bharatiya Janata Party. The writer of her Wikipedia page also bestows her the title of Uttarakhand Maata, although our team could neither validate the authenticity of the title nor of its award.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rekha’s singular claim to fame is from mid-2016, when she was a Congress legislator, went missing for four days, and then turned up to the assembly as a BJP member in an attempt to oust the then Congress Chief Minister.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Cow is the only animal that not only inhales oxygen, but also exhales it.”
~ Rekha Arya, circa 2018, as Minister of Animal Husbandry, Uttarakhand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, we do not contest that cows exhale oxygen, but it is not the only species, by far. Every species inhales oxygen and exhales oxygen, and also nitrogen, and argon, and carbon dioxide, and trace amounts of neon, helium, methane, krypton, and hydrogen. &lt;em&gt;You&lt;/em&gt; inhale all of it. And then your lungs take up some of the oxygen and then returns the rest back. There is no magical barrier at the nose that stops all the gases except for oxygen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve not got the gist of it already, then let us spell it out for you. No, cows do not produce oxygen. No animal does, which at the end of the day, what a cow is. It is just an animal, which we exploit more so than others probably, but that is a discussion for another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The cow is treated as an incarnation of motherhood. The cow’s milk is scientifically considered the best for a newborn after his mother’s milk.”
~ Rekha Arya, circa 2018, seeking the status of ‘Rashtra Mata’ for the cow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we found no scientific literature to support her claim, we did find &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.euro.who.int/__data/assets/pdf_file/0004/98302/WS_115_2000FE.pdf&quot;&gt;a World Health Organisation advisory&lt;/a&gt; noting that unmodified cow’s milk should not be fed to infants. As a minister who holds both the portfolios of Women and Child Welfare, and Animal Husbandry, this is stupid at best and directly endangering the lives of infants at worst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also to be noted that she very freely used the term “scientifically” with no citation of real research, which, no surprises, has fooled a lot of gullible people. She managed to get the resolution seeking the status of ‘rashtra mata’ for the cow passed through the Uttarakhand assembly unanimously. She then went on to talk about the “medicinal qualities” of cow urine…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We found this draft in front of an unconscious correspondent who has since been diagnosed with Post Research Stress Disorder. In honour of our asylum-bound correspondent, we have kept the draft unedited.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Rekha-Arya-is-Stupid/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Rekha-Arya-is-Stupid/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>EdTech Grassroots Aggregator Dot-com Baju's Disrupts Market</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;edtech-grassroots-aggregator-dot-com-bajus-disrupts-market&quot;&gt;EdTech Grassroots Aggregator Dot-com Baju’s Disrupts Market&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;vow-not-to-be-another-brick-in-the-paywall&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vow not to be another brick in the paywall&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hubli, April 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: A locally grown educational technology start-up, Baju’s-dot-com, has gone viral in the last fortnight. The banner advertisement free platform acts as an online classifieds board for local tuition teachers for school-going children. Generating revenue only through small fees collected from advertising teachers, they expect to turn profitable with scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all began as a small group project in the TiE Young Entrepreneurs Program 2020. The project brought together 23 tuition teachers in the city to advertise their classes on their platform and saw a significant spike in student enrolments after. It was no surprise when the group were awarded first place in TiECON Hubli 2021. Following an incubation of two months, the company has now gone national.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our platform unites all the small and fragmented tuition teachers across the country. It gives those tuition teachers who teach just 10-15 students a fighting chance against the big companies with all their million dollar marketing teams that can build big enough lies and stories and endorsements,” said an emotionally charged Ms. Doddamani, co-founder and CEO of Baju’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents in the city believe that Baju’s offers the personal touch that is so essential in education and that which is morbidly lacking in both over-crowded schools and “online education”. “The teachers at school don’t have enough time to pay attention to my kid and repeat and explain subject matter. That is why my kid now goes to Ms. Hosmani’s classes to clear his doubts and practice,” said Mrs. Hanchinmani, an involved parent. Ms. Hosmani has added 5 new students to her tuition classes after listing on Baju’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In just two days of national operations, over 200 tuition teachers from all over the country have listed their classes on Baju’s online platform. The CEO further envisions to add services for hobby/extracurricular trainers soon. Expected categories of classes to be found on the platform include dance, drawing, music, martial arts, and more. With such an open platform, imagination alone is the limit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Baju's-Classes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Baju's-Classes/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rohit Shetty's Cop Universe to get The Avengers-esque ensemble alien threat movie</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;rohit-shettys-cop-universe-to-get-the-avengers-2012-style-ensemble-alien-threat-movie&quot;&gt;Rohit Shetty’s Cop Universe To Get The Avengers (2012) Style Ensemble Alien Threat Movie&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;stunt-directors-and-vfx-artists-remain-unconcerned&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stunt directors and VFX artists remain unconcerned&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bombay, March 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Over the past decade, most successful (quantified by revenue) Hollywood movies have belonged to one or the other superhero franchises. Picking up on that trend, Bollywood might be on the cusp of getting such a franchise of its own. With Singham (2011), Simmba (2018), and Sooryavanshi (2021) establishing three separate S-heavy^ heroes in Rohit Shetty’s Cop Universe, an ensemble movie is slated to be released next year to bring the shared cop universe together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Film pundits suggest that this might be Reliance Entertainment’s attempt to become Disney. After acquiring DreamWorks Pictures and other big production companies over the years, it is set to establish its own shared universe. “We wouldn’t be surprised if they set up a Cop Universe theme park next. It will be a riot,” said Ms. Swadeshi Kaur, a purveyor of Indian films.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rohit Shetty, director of all the movies in the Cop Universe, is known to be looking for indigenous inspiration for the upcoming ensemble movie. At the top of the inspirational list is the &lt;em&gt;Life OK&lt;/em&gt; hit television show, &lt;strong&gt;SuperCops vs Supervillains&lt;/strong&gt;. “There are over 500 episodes in the show. I have spent most of the lockdown watching, analysing, and taking down notes,” said a very sleep deprived Rohit Shetty. “But the science fiction is so fictional and the horror is so horrifying. It’s all worth it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Shetty believes that Indian producers and directors are just not ambitious enough. Big budget superhero movies with explicitly and exquisitely placed humour is today’s zeitgeist, and we are falling behind. “If people want flying cars, exploding power plants, falling buildings, piercing head shots, spandex-wearing know-it-all rogues, and of course earth-levelling megalomaniac green aliens, we should give it to them,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RS’s CU currently has 3 blockbuster movies, 1 more in the making, 2 currently running spin-off animated television shows, and 2 video games. The ensemble movie, rumoured to be titled Sammelan, is expected to be the capstone of Phase One and lead to a bunch of more work in Phase Two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a recent interview, actor Akshay Kumar said he was ready to be an indigenous superhero. “My manager is in talks with Rohit to add superpowers to my character,” he said. Upon being asked about the powers he already has in the movie, he said, “Yeah, yeah, we have the power of patriotism and incorruptibility and super-strength and flight and all, but I want real superpowers like heat-vision and time bending.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;^ S for hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: We also like how RSCU is an EE away from RESCUE.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Rohit-Shetty's-Cop-Universe/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Rohit-Shetty's-Cop-Universe/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cops burn confiscated marijuana; Students stoned</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;cops-burn-confiscated-marijuana-students-stoned&quot;&gt;Cops burn confiscated marijuana. Students stoned.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;canopy-growth-corporation-stock-price-surges-after-a-wsb-meme&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Canopy Growth Corporation stock price surges after a WSB meme&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manipal, March 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: In an unusual turn of events, Manipal police burned 25 kilograms of marijuana confiscated from residents of Manipal Institute of Technology’s Student Hostel C, behind the hostel. Students who had thought they got away with murder were surprised to find that they would get to relish the harvest too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Police raids in MIT hostels has been recurrent in the past few years. There was a significant downtick in the number of raids during the lockdown, when the students had been sent home, but it failed to reach zero. Changes in mayoral and police administrations have failed to move the issue to a conclusion. It is now a well-known fact that the police department recruits 18-year-olds right out of school to be trained as informants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest round of raids, conducted last week, were unusual due to the spike in rumours of collusion. Rumours have surfaced that a last minute deal was struck between the raiding cops and the local marijuana dealers. It is believed that the cops were paid cash upwards of two lakhs each to burn the confiscated contraband in the premises itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“(This) allows the dealers to introduce their product to new customers and ensures that the police continue to make easy money extorting twenty year old kids,” said Jatayu Hans, student secretary of Hostel C. “It’s really a win-win situation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the viral spread of Mr. Hans’ interview, the Union Home Affairs Ministry has ordered a CBI probe into the issue. The State Home Affairs Ministry has reprimanded the behaviour of the police and have promised to take recreational drug usage and enforcement against it more seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few students were interviewed in the aftermath of the burning of the marijuana behind the hostel. When asked about the detrimental effects it can have on the lungs, a red-eyed garrulous twenty-two year old answered, “I am training to be a pulmonologist. Trust me. It’s not a problem.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, an MIT student was diagnosed with a concussion after being hit on the head with a hard solid non-metallic mineral matter by a stoner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Cops-burn-weed/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Cops-burn-weed/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Feminists accuse Lux Cozy of promoting domestic abuse; Seek redressal</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;feminists-accuse-lux-cozy-of-promoting-domestic-abuse-seek-redressal&quot;&gt;Feminists accuse Lux Cozy of promoting domestic abuse. Seek redressal.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;maniesh-pauls-rs-13k-big-logo-sneakers-have-huge-stripes-that-live-up-to-its-name-mensxp&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maniesh Paul’s Rs 13K ‘Big Logo’ Sneakers Have Huge Stripes That Live Up To Its Name: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mensxp.com/fashion/celebrity-style/86406-maniesh-pauls-rs-13k-big-logo-sneakers-have-huge-stripes-that-live-up-to-its-name.html&quot;&gt;MensXP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coonoor, March 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: “Beat Your Meat. Not Your Wife.” read a prominent placard at the front of the protest at the Lux Cozy manufacturing unit in the city. Two days ago, over 200 feminists participated in a protest march, followed by four hours of non-violent obstruction of manufacturing, to display their resentment at wife beaters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wife beating is a historical patriarchal wrong in the global society. Domestic abuse starts at home. Redressal need not,” expounded Ms. Sati Savitri (name changed) in front of the gathered populace. “Companies like Lux Cozy that make wife beaters are to blame for propagating such abuse and they should be punished.” The protest ended after some participants began burning wife beaters in the middle of the road and police had to politely ask everyone to disperse for fear of violence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a reactionary response, a motley group of a dozen middle aged men prominently wearing wife beaters began protesting in front of the City Hall at midday. When asked about why they were protesting, they failed to form a coherent response. A lack of leadership at the rally was evident. An hour into the unclear protest, two dupattas were burned. When asked about the burning, they said, “well, they did it first.” Police quickly cleared the air and the City Hall steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;News of the two protests soon became a national talking point. Prominent television news channels held debates on the issue at prime time. Indian National Congress spokespeople blamed the government for the historical wrong and demanded an apology from the Prime Minister. Bharatiya Janata Party spokespeople blamed the previous governments for the historical wrong and demanded that INC issue the apology. The CPI(M) was unavailable for comment citing urgent meetings to formulate solutions to the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A panel of satirists and comics had a less heated debate on YouTube Live and came to the consensus that while the issue of wife beaters was stupid, acquiescing to not calling them wife beaters was sensible. They too held that the name was misleading and even though wife beaters had little to actually do with wife beating, it could confuse some wife beater wearers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The panel suggests everyone to use the term Baniyans instead. The Baniya community is aggressively confused about the issue and believing that this re-branding might exacerbate caste system wounds, have declared that they might form a protest march this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Wife-Beaters/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Wife-Beaters/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>WhatsApp introduces new features for the Tone Deaf</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;whatsapp-introduces-new-features-for-the-tone-deaf&quot;&gt;WhatsApp introduces new features for the tone deaf&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;applications-open-for-translator-to-aid-in-interview-with-telegram-ceo&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Applications open for translator to aid in interview with Telegram CEO&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gokak/Gurugram, March 2021:&lt;/strong&gt; Following the recent promising results in beta testing, Whatsapp India is set to launch a swathe of new features in the market. In an exclusive interview with The Hindustan Grimes, WhatsApp India’s Chief of Operations, Mr. Shabdh Ghosh, makes some groundbreaking announcements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This transcript has been lightly edited for clarity and abridged for brevity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It seems that WhatsApp as a whole is having a new moment. You’re the old player in a market where customers seem to be getting disillusioned. What changes are you bringing to your product, and likely, to the other products in the market?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. We have a range of changes that we’ve tried and tested in the beta program and are ready to bring to the market. Our top new feature is the &lt;em&gt;tone-aid&lt;/em&gt; for the emotionally challenged community and for just about anyone who’s just tired of figuring out signals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many companies are now vying to increase everyone’s IQ, we thought we’d try and augment everyone’s EQ instead. &lt;em&gt;Tone-aid&lt;/em&gt; makes it really easy to read the tone of the conversation, be it a sarcastic friend, a depressed cousin, or a bewildering group chat. WhatsApp will automatically set the background of the chat to a different colour to indicate the mood of the texts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is going to be a game changer and help us keep our customers happy, or sad, or respectful, or whatever the emotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wait! Doesn’t that void the end-to-end encryption of the messages?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are now disillusioned about the end-to-end anyway. They know the reality. So our team thought we might as well try to roll out new features to aid our customers. We want to give our customers the best features they deserve. For free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hmm. We at the Grimes are agog to see how the customers will see this rollout. Are you at all concerned about your more privacy-focused competitors like Telegram and Signal?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nah. It’s all just a fad. We saw their numbers increase in January and then fall again in February. Our numbers have stayed steady. The fad will pass. We’re not worried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right. So it would appear that the customers are not really concerned about their privacy at all. Is that so?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. That’s what we saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month we tried out a new feature in beta where our AI helps you synthesise replies based on the detected or a custom chosen sentiment. Most of our beta testers loved it. They loved that we could help them create funny replies based on who they were talking to, instantaneously. It just works so great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You say most of them liked. So there were people who didn’t like it. What do you expect went wrong there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, there were just a few mishaps. Sometimes stubby fingered customers find it hard to click on the right options in our UI. It can’t be helped. This one time clicking on the wrong custom sentiment resulted in an inappropriate situation. One of our betas ended up sending “Yo momma so old, she fukin’ died” instead of condolences, on hearing their boss’ mother passing away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oof. That is horrible. That seems like a major oversight on the part of your te—&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. No. No. It wasn’t really a big problem. The beta contacted us quickly, so we were able to unsend that message and not leave a trace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, some other betas heard of the story and requested an option where the AI would synthesize replies based on an arbitrary sentiment. They want a random mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And will you be acquiescing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course. Who are we to deny what our customers want. And anyway it was an easy modification to our powerful AI. It can track the mood of the conversations while also supplementing those inferences with precise knowledge of the sender’s behaviour and cycles. It can track the changes with respect to diurnal or nocturnal cycles, moon cycles, and even seasons and semesters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Woah! It seems like you are ready to bring the AI revolution to messaging. Do you expect the market to take in these changes easily?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will always be friction. But if we bring the changes quickly, it will quickly go from the normal to a new normal and it’ll all be alright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not nearly done with the changes anyway. Our latest beta test was automated replies. It turned out that “I am fine mom.” and “Happy b’day …!” turned out to be the most used auto-replies. We think this is going to be a big hit too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mr. Shabdh Ghosh explained more planned features set to be released on April 1st. A more detailed transcript of the interview can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whatsapp.com/legal/updates/privacy-policy/?lang=en&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Whatsapp++/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Whatsapp++/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Teachers to teach only 50% syllabus this year</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;teachers-to-teach-only-50-syllabus-this-year&quot;&gt;Teachers To Teach Only 50% Syllabus This Year&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;karnataka-hc-orders-release-of-prisoners-at-half-term&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Karnataka HC orders release of prisoners at half term&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bengaluru, March 2021:&lt;/strong&gt; Private school teachers in the Bengaluru Urban district have been instructed by their managements to halt teaching at 50% of the syllabus to show their displeasure at the government’s order to slash tuition fees by 50%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On January 30th, the Karnataka government came out with an order to slash all private school tuition fees by 30%, in order to ease the burden on pandemic-affected parents. While parents were relieved, school managements were irked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schools have claimed that this fee cut will render them unable to pay their teachers. Parents are unanimous in their dismissal of this argument. They claim that the schools have already fired many teachers and cut the salaries of the rest severely, citing the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On February 23rd, after no rollback of the fee slash order, Karnataka Private School Managements, Teaching, and Non-Teaching Staff Coordination Committee (KPMTCC)^, representing all the private schools protested by taking out a march from the Central Railway Station to Freedom Park. Over 25,000, wiling and unwilling, teaching and non-teaching staff participated in the protest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is difficult for school managements to sustain the operations of the school, especially after the COVID-19 pandemic, if fees are slashed,” said Bangalore International Public School Trustee, Mr. K D Fiddler. “The objective of the protest is the financial distress of private education institutions and their managements. I might have to liquidise some offshore investments to pay for the new Lamborghini Sian if parents don’t pay all of the school fees.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vexed by the pettiness of school managements, the Karnataka government has doubled down on their decision. On March 3rd, the government announced that schools wouldn’t be allowed to collect more than 50% of the tuition fees, to the jubilation of all parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, in this latest exchange between private educational institutions and the government, KPMTCC has instructed all school managements to ensure that their school teachers only teach 50% of the syllabus to the students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At same time, the Karnataka Private Schools’ Parents’ Associations’ Coordination Committee (KPSPACC)^ have called this a spiteful move on the part of the schools and have demanded the government to stop them. The KPSPACC warns that failure to stop the move would result in protest marches in the city and a possible Karnataka Bandh next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;^Both these committees are real. Google them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Halftime-Teachers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Halftime-Teachers/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Popular celebrity loses battle against weakened vision</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;popular-celebrity-loses-battle-against-weakened-vision&quot;&gt;Popular Celebrity Loses Battle Against Weakened Vision&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;rumours-of-actress-sudarshinis-stolen-bookmark-debunked-by-fact-checkers-who-revealed-she-cannot-read&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rumours of Actress Sudarshini’s stolen bookmark debunked by fact checkers who revealed she cannot read.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bollywood, March 2021:&lt;/strong&gt; In a bizarre turn of events, popular Bollywood actor, Muscle “Severe Body Image” Khan, has been reported to have lost his glasses. Reports also suggest he tried looking, but couldn’t see. The glasses were a top of the line product of High Costoso brand in Merengue Yellow shade with a Stannic finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Muscle Khan was observed struggling to perform his day-to-day activities like body building et cetera without his High Costoso glasses. He took to instagram to confide in his followers about the struggles a celebrity faces on a daily basis. Social media was abuzz with tales of celebrity struggles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitterati all over the country have sympathised with Mr. Khan’s plight. A GoFundMe for Mr. Khan’s glasses has collected over 15 Rupees. Additionally, a petition to have all glasses mandatorily contain a GPS tracker has garnered over 34 signatures on change.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An hour later, a new pair of High Costoso glasses was delivered to his residence in Dharavi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: The pandemic has celebrity culture imploding so badly, celebrities are paying us to keep them in the news cycle and have them remain relevant. Hence, this is a sponsored article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared in The Hindustan Times.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/celebrity-culture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/celebrity-culture/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>McDonald's Burger Flippers to Work from Home</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;mcdonalds-burger-flippers-to-work-from-home&quot;&gt;McDonald’s Burger Flippers to Work from Home&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mint-workers-request-to-make-money-at-home&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mint workers request to make money at home&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Navi Mumbai, March 2021:&lt;/strong&gt; McDonald’s India has struck an unusual tripartite collaboration with Reliance Jio and Vaastav: The Virtual Pvt. Ltd. in order to allow some of their kitchen employees to work from home. State-of-the-art Virtual Reality and Robotics technology will be used to enable the cooks to control the robots in the kitchen from the comfort of their homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In order for the technology to work, we need humongous internet bandwidths both at our outlets and the employees’ homes,” said Mr. Raj “Burger Raja” Bargu, CEO of McDonald’s India. “We approached Jio for the internet, but they offered to be a collaborator for free publicity instead of a vendor.” Rumours have sprung up that Jio is in talks to acquire Vastav: The Virtual Pvt. Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McDonald’s move to virtual comes at the wake of a spring of new COVID19 cases in Maharashtra, which news outlets have dubbed the Second Wave. Maharashtra’s State Task Force and the State Surveillance Officer, Dr. Satish Power have said: “No.” Dr. Power added, “This is not the second wave. That happened during Ganesh Chaturthi. We’re likely in the fourth wave now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also caused a bout of frenzy on Dalal Street. Stock prices of Swiggy and Zomato dropped immediately after news of the Virtual Move spread. After a few hours of heated discussions and explanations of the new technology, the market breathed a sigh of relief. Swiggy and Zomato stock prices have slowly returned to pre-frenzy levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first phase of the virtual trials are set to begin next Monday in 5 outlets in Navi Mumbai. “We have already trained over 30 cooks,” said Burger Raja. “It is really simple to operate. It’s just like playing ‘Papa’s Burgeria’.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;News of now dubbed “Virtual Burgers” has spread through Navi Mumbai. Navi Mumbaikars appear excited about something new coming in their city. But experts refrain from optimism. “This might have the opposite effect,” says, Dr. Sonu Sodabottleopenerwala, popular food enthusiast and blogger. “People will flock there and COVID19 spread will only increase.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology enthusiasts have also hurrahed at the move. Healthy eating advocates have had mixed reactions. “We want to see the machines rise,” said Mr. Goli Pav, a former foodie, “but no sugar please.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Burgers-+-VR-WfH/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Burgers-+-VR-WfH/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Depressed? We have the solution: Govt.</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;depressed-we-have-the-solution-says-govt&quot;&gt;“Depressed? We have the solution” Says Govt.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;hotel-trivago&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hotel? Trivago^&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prayagraj, February 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: With the rise in awareness about mental health, depression, and suicides, the central government has been under fire for not acknowledging the harsh reality and ignoring the plight of the mentally ill. Keyboard warriors have taken to twitter to talk about how depression is eating them up. After weeks of silence, the government has spoken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Central Government advises youth to sleep on time, wake up at sunrise, and perform Surya Namaskar. They say that this is the &lt;em&gt;Ram Baan&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Panacea&lt;/em&gt; (for English readers) or Cure-all (for less educated English readers) for depression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All this hullabaloo about psychiatry and western medicine is fake news spread by the opposition. It is not real,” propounds AJP spokesperson, Ram Mandirwale. “If kids just wake up early, perform yoga, and join their local AJP IT Cell WhatsApp group, everything will be good.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This advisory comes in the wake of the backlash faced by the Prime Minister’s Office for their recent tweet about depression. The tweet, dated February 14, read: “Say No to Depression. If your friends offer you a bandwagon seat onto depression, just say no. #NoFOMO #NoFad #NoDepression #JustSayNo” Thousands of what can only be categorised as the depressed youth demographic tweeted back: “no u.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Depression is as stupid as lactose intolerance. Just tolerate it.” says chief advisor to the AYUSH minister. He adds, “Depression is just a state of mind. But the Minister really believes in what people send him on WhatsApp. So we humour him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popular pseudoscience proponent and part-time Member of Paliament, Smt. Sthan Dharak Ji has obtained records from the parliament’s in house therapist. Speaking at a press release, she eviscerated Opposition Deputy Chief for being weak and the Home Minister’s deputy for faking depression. Smt. Sthan Dharak Ji and the therapist in question are under investigation for breaking therapist-patient privilege.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;^Unpaid Promo&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Depressing-Solutions/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Depressing-Solutions/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chronically constipated man keeps shark in bathroom. PETA furious.</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;chronically-constipated-man-keeps-shark-in-bathroom-peta-furious&quot;&gt;Chronically constipated man keeps shark in bathroom. PETA furious.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;peta-india-recommends-reading-animal-farm-for-cultivating-love-for-animals&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PETA India recommends reading Animal Farm for cultivating love for animals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dalhousie, February 2021:&lt;/strong&gt; A retired Himachal dentist went viral in January for his unusual solution to chronic constipation. “It all started with the Blue Planet and David Attenborough,” says Dr. P Aware, connoisseur of erratic bowels and fear tactics. “I was watching a bit of the Blue Planet in VR and that was when I had the best bowel movements since back when I was ragged in college. I &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to go from virtual to real. And so, I made a few calls.” The Grimes, at this time, is not predisposed to revealing the contacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the viral spread of the shark tank in the toilet episode, PETA India filed a complaint with the District Court in Delhi asking for injunctive relief, whereupon the judge dismissed their plea and asked them to look-up the term “jurisdiction”. Following the debacle, PETA India sought donations to send a representative to Himachal Pradesh. Two days later, a case was filed in the Chamba District Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Aware has countersued PETA India for vexatious litigation and has demanded additional companion sharks in damages. As evident from our coverage of &lt;a href=&quot;https://thegrimes.substack.com/p/true-crime-pays&quot;&gt;Dr. Someshwar’s report on pending cases&lt;/a&gt; in Indian courts, this pair of cases is not expected to be resolved anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is bullshit. He can’t use animals like this,” said Ms. P A Sugamana, spokesperson for PETA India. Adventurer and television presenter Bear Grylls added, “Yeah, sharks are so hard to care for. I can get you a good deal on gharials. (They are) easier to keep but just as scary.” “Take my tiger,” said an amused Joe Exotic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New developments have come to the fore in a twitter update by Dr. Aware. He has claimed that over the past few weeks PETA India has employed goondas and Bar Council enrolled goondas to intimidate him into releasing the shark. “This has played into my hands,” said an elated Dr. Aware. “I have had some of the best bowel movements ever.” He is known to have replaced his shark tank with high quality images of PETA representatives, lawyers and goondas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/fear-factor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/fear-factor/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unfluencers Anonymous expands For Dummies series with *Influencing For Dummies*</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;unfluencers-anonymous-expands-for-dummies-series-with-influencing-for-dummies&quot;&gt;Unfluencers Anonymous expands For Dummies series with &lt;em&gt;Influencing For Dummies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;book-now-a-recommended-reading-for-nation-for-namo-aspirants&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Book now a recommended reading for Nation for NaMo Aspirants&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The World Wide Web, February 2021:&lt;/strong&gt; The For Dummies series is well known for bringing specific domain knowledge to laymen in an easily digestible manner. In its latest addition, it brought to the masses the hip and trending craft of influencing others into agreeing to having advertisements shoved their throats. The book was released by &lt;strong&gt;Panda Book Home (PBH)&lt;/strong&gt; in Autumn 2020, and was the result of over a decade of rigorous research by Armenian researchers, Dr. K’oob Ecaf and Dr. Margat Sni. The book was a bust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book sold exactly 37 copies, with the authors buying around 25 of those to gift to friends and family. PBH Executive Ida Rathernot was appalled by the sales, but defended the authors vehemently. “This is to be expected during the release of a book whose target readership has the attention span of a goldfish. We expect that, over time, this book will become a cult classic, much like the film &lt;strong&gt;The Room&lt;/strong&gt;,” she said. “In the meantime, we will be utilising other rather unconventional methods for publicity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PBH has reportedly hired over 73 influencers to publicise this book by using Instagram Reels to summarise the book. Among the influencers hired was Anand Mitali, who we had reached out to for a comment on an unrelated story. He spoke to us at length over the phone. “Books are making less and less sense in the modern world. Man has not evolved to read 300 page theses on base superstructure theory. We have evolved to consume information in byte sized chunks, like the 280 characters of a tweet, or the screenshots of the tweet on Instagram. So it makes sense that modern bookhouses would turn to us to publicise their new books. However, it took me 3 months to read the book, reading two pages a day.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other influencers further confirmed that they had received pre-prints of the book many months in advance, and had been using the theories extolled in the book to improve their reach. One influencer confirmed that she improved her reach by over 300% using the book. On the other hand, actor and fervent patriot Akshay Kumar took to &lt;a href=&quot;http://kooapp.com&quot;&gt;Koo&lt;/a&gt; to talk about his experience growing followers. “These new trends to improve influencing having been made abroad. I’ve had an exponential growth in my Koo followers. 2X in 25 days. The Aatmanirbhar methods are always better. #IndiaTogether”^ he wrote on Koo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;book-review-influencing-for-dummies&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Book Review: Influencing for Dummies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hindustan Grimes’ Editorial Board&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;**&lt;/em&gt;Dr. Ecaf and Dr. Sni delve into the psychological aspects of influencing, and offer an actionable plan to improve growth while emphasising on what the influencers should keep front and centre: monetisation. While the book is a must read for all influencers, it is unclear if the book will ever reach the intended audience, and this is not so much an indictment of the authors than it is a statement on the state of affairs of the modern world. However, a must read for any average bibliophile with a voracious appetite for knowledge. 5/7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;^Translated from Hindi&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Influencing-for-Dummies/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Influencing-for-Dummies/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Poor man cannot afford dentist; Superglues son's teeth together</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;poor-man-cannot-afford-dentist-superglues-sons-teeth-together&quot;&gt;Poor man cannot afford dentist. Superglues son’s teeth together.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;unarmed-man-robs-prosthetics-shop-police-attempt-to-disarm-and-unarm-the-consequently-armed-man&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unarmed man robs prosthetics shop. Police attempt to disarm and unarm the consequently armed man.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Belgavi, February 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: A mob comprising victims of insurance non-payouts, interested citizens, people of irregular teeth, and idle yet enthusiastic college students broke into The Insurance* company’s premises and staged a protest. Having caught the security detail off-guard, the enthusiastic college students began a flash mob routine to the tune of “Mo Money Mo Problems.” They were quickly shut down by the rest of the protesters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon inquiry about the structure of the “protest group”, the mob failed to produce a leader and told us that they joined together over instructions from an anonymously curated Google Doc. “We paid our health insurance premiums thinking we’ll be covered for when something goes wrong. Who do we turn to when The Insurance company also does us wrong?” asked D. Kanti (name unconfirmed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After receiving some aid from the police department to clear the mob from the premises, the health insurance company’s PR team held a press conference to clarify the facts of the case. “There is no case,” said The Insurance* representative. “We expressly obtain signatures from our customers on documents that say we are liable for nothing and can payout at our discretion, in small print of course.” She added, “dental problems are not real problems. If they can’t eat bread, let them drink smoothies.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recent protests and debates among various stakeholders of the health insurance industry follows the viral spread of the story of Danesh Doot’s dismal dentistry. Unable to afford a dentist’s services, Danesh fixed his son, Megh’s broken teeth with superglue. Due to excess glue, the quackery victim found his jaws glued together and had to be fed nasally. A successful GoFundMe campaign over the last week has enabled Megh to get a dental surgery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the National Dentists’ Association held a high level meeting and released a press statement yesterday. “We cannot stand by and watch while radiology departments in big hospitals claim unreasonably big expenses and get paid by the health insurance companies, when we, dentists, take the most x-rays,” said Dr. May Svalk, chief spokesperson of the NDA. “We want health insurance policies to cover our work too. We are just as important.” The NDA has called upon the government to organise talks between the NDA and the insurance companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Health and Family Welfare has formed a Department of Dentistry (or DoD) to coordinate with and consider the pleas of the various stakeholders of the issue. The Ministry failed to respond to tweets inquiring whether dental costs would be covered under National Health Protection plans like Ayushman Bharat in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*The Insurance to End All Insurances Inc. TM&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/superglue-teeth/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/superglue-teeth/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HC Judge notes the astounding number of peding cases in 500-page opinion piece</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;hc-judge-notes-the-astounding-number-of-pending-cases-in-500-page-opinion-piece&quot;&gt;HC Judge Notes the Astounding Number of Pending Cases in 500-page Opinion Piece&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lakshyadweep-hc-judge-tries-joining-online-panel-discussion-fails-due-to-bad-jio-connection&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lakshyadweep HC Judge tries joining online panel discussion; fails due to bad Jio connection.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bombay, February 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Reputed Bombay High Court Judge, Dr. Adinath Someshwar, has returned from his two month sabbatical with a strongly worded opinion piece on the worsening case of the judiciary in the country. The opinion piece was expeditiously published in a special edition of the Indian Law Review, titled “You Ain’t Got Served? Oops.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The comprehensive, and possibly exhaustive, 500-page monograph begins and ends with the dismal situation of the pendency of cases at all levels of the judiciary. There are instances mentioned where suspects, after being denied bail, have spent more time in imprisonment awaiting trial than the maximum prison term carried on their charges. Even among those who have been convicted, hearings for appeals have been pending longer than their sentences. While no one &lt;em&gt;wants&lt;/em&gt; to take away the right to appeal, the “chronic pendency of criminal appeals” is a major challenge to the judiciary system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a significant correlation between pendency of cases in a region and the judicial vacancies. Many high courts have vacancies of over a third or more of the sanctioned strength of the court. Some of the district and taluka courts are worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Jobs for upholding the law, and in some places, upholding the law itself, is just not in vogue,” says Dr. Someshwar. “With a population of over 1.3 billion to look after, reform is needed to attract more human resources toward taking positions in the judiciary.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are over 3.4 crore pending cases in the District and Taluka courts of India, 78% of which are more than one year old. There are more than 85 thousand cases which have been pending execution for over 30 years now. There are over 85 lakh pending cases in the High Courts of India, 85% of which are more than one year old. Even in the Supreme Court, there are over 60 thousand pending cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many prominent members of the judiciary have come forward praising the monograph and have written editorials about it. “It is high time for reform in the judiciary,” said a judge from the Mizoram High Court. Meanwhile, the ongoing strike in Jantar Mantar calling for reduction in work hours for judges continues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/pending-cases/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/pending-cases/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Numerologist charged with 13 counts of assault and battery requests additional charge</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;numerologist-charged-with-13-counts-of-assault-and-battery-requests-additional-charge&quot;&gt;Numerologist charged with 13 counts of assault and battery requests additional charge.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sex-offender-sentenced-to-68-years-of-imprisonment-requests-an-additional-year&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sex offender sentenced to 68 years of imprisonment requests an additional year&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pali, February 2021:&lt;/strong&gt; Number Baba (name changed), until 3 months ago, was an honest numerologist conducting his practice in the city. On the 26th of January, Number Baba was caught participating in a street brawl cum lynching and promptly arrested by Pali Police, locally known as the Palice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ardent followers of Baba have taken to the streets and social media to protest and express their displeasure at the high-profile arrest. Media has been abuzz with stories of disruption of normalcy in the town. In the lead up to the trial, protesters claim the law has no standing to try a man of such scientific knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the preliminary hearing on Wednesday, Number Baba pleaded innocence, but requested the prosecutor to add an additional charge to the 13 counts in his charge-sheet. He held that 13 was an unlucky number and that he would not win his case otherwise. While the prosecutor and the judge laughed and consequently ignored him, he tried to forcefully get another charge by attempting to beat up the stenographer in the court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That was our ploy all along,” said the defence lawyer in the press conference after the hearing. “Laws and courts are mere acute peculiarities in front of the vast expanse of knowledge of numerology.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The judge held Number Baba in contempt of court for causing disturbance in the court proceedings and cancelled his bail. Baba’s numerology services still remain active through Signal and Telegram. (For latest active phone numbers and domains, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stopclickingunknown.links/&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are confident that Number Baba will be let off soon,” said his assistant, Numeral Kumar (number changed), optimistically. “We have the numbers on our side.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/court-hearing-numerologist/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/court-hearing-numerologist/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Talk Delivered on Nobel Prize winning work from Faculty of IIT Madras</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;talk-delivered-on-nobel-prize-winning-work-from-faculty-of-iit-madras&quot;&gt;Talk Delivered on Nobel Prize winning work from Faculty of IIT Madras&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;work-done-by-researchers-presented-by-iitm-faculty&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Work done by researchers; Presented by IITM Faculty&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chennai, January 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: The Faculty Association of IIT Madras and the Office of the Alumni and Corporate Relations, IITM have come together to organise a faculty colloquium under the newly formed working group, Nobel Talks at Gajendra Circle. Due to the presence of multiple Covid 19 active cases in the institute campus and the consequent curfew introduced, the actual talks have had to be shifted to Google Meets instead. (Zoom refused to send quotations; was deemed too expensive.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We wanted to be noble like the Stoics. Yes. We sent in applications for a dais and a lectern and possibly a theatre to be set up at the Gajendra Circle but the administration did not acquiesce. However, this has not dampened our spirit. We shall continue with our pursuit for knowledge.” said AGK, the charismatic secretary of the faculty association, with an air of gusto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, the second talk in a series concerning the recent works which were awarded the Nobel Prize by IIT Madras faculty was held. The talk was about the contribution of Prof. John B. Goodenough to the design and development of Lithium ion Batteries, which won him the Nobel Prize in Chemistry in the year 2019. His expertise in solid state physics and magnetism had led to a systematic investigation and development of cathode materials suitable for LIB applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick searches by the editorial team revealed that Prof. Goodenough had no affiliations with IIT Madras. Many, including us, were duped by the dubious titling into getting hyped up for such pioneering research being done in such close vicinity to us. Enthusiastic, and slightly proudly patriotic, students were disappointed nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence: Pioneering work was done. A Nobel Prize was awarded. Meanwhile, IITM faculty are talking about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dubious, and sometimes downright false, claims aren’t a new occurrence in the scientific world, which is essentially the world. While it is easier to see how money can be a persuasive motive, propping up charades like Theranos, which, at one point, was worth billions of dollars, there exists the call of fame, a motive just as strong. A 2009 systematic review and meta-analysis of survey data found that about 2% of scientists admitted to falsifying, fabricating, or modifying data at least once. [1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fanelli D. How Many Scientists Fabricate and Falsify Research? A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Survey Data. Tregenza T, editor. PLoS ONE. 2009;4: e5738. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0005738&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/bullshit-marketing-1-insti-email-subject-parody/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/bullshit-marketing-1-insti-email-subject-parody/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Army signs deal with Lithuanian Company. Sri(x4) Amar calls for reform.</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;army-signs-deal-with-lithuanian-company-srix4-amar-angry-calls-for-reform&quot;&gt;Army Signs Deal with Lithuanian Company. Sri(x4) Amar Angry. Calls for reform.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;kautilyas-arthashastra-jumps-to-1-on-amazonin&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kautilya’s Arthashastra jumps to #1 on amazon.in&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Delhi, January 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Sri Sri Sri Sri Amar Ji holds that Lord Ram invented the first night vision device and it is a disgrace that we have to get “modern” tech from outside India. Enunciating heavy lines from the scriptures, he expounds why modern isn’t necessarily better; says fire is still awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This government and these procurement boards are full of corrupt politicians, quixotic soldiers, and naive engineers. Do they not see that this company is selling us product (sic) that is inferior to our own? Do they do it for money, pride, and technology?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quoting Adi Shankaracharya’s rhetoric, Amar Ji tells us, “Who but the Atman is capable of removing the bonds of ignorance, passion, and self-interested action? Who but us can rid ourselves of the ignorant technology that these selfish companies so passionately sell us?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heeding to Amar Ji’s call to action, many spiritual men have come forward and volunteered to sit on government committees for defence procurement, education policy, financial planning etc. It is no false matter that these men have an exemplary record of leadership, wealth accumulation, and alternative education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Economists and academicians are hailing this a Hail Mary. Popular science communicator and IIT Goa faculty member Dr. Samar Sardi tweeted, “We’re all going to die. #AmarNoMore”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As direct representatives of supreme beings and backed my millions of ardent followers, the men of the gods have come to describe this as a true victory of democracy. They have however declined to be corrupted by such things as income tax returns and criminal investigations. As a compromise though, they have offered discounts for purifying the offices and bureaus of such entities. There really is no end to their humility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/night-vision-device/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/night-vision-device/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chameleon Corps lost behind enemy lines</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;chameleon-corps-lost-behind-enemy-lines&quot;&gt;Chameleon Corps Lost Behind Enemy Lines&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;inspires-yo-yo-honey-singh-hit-single-chameleons-be-chameleonin&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inspires Yo Yo Honey Singh Hit Single “Chameleons be Chameleonin’”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Siachen, January 2021:&lt;/strong&gt; The Grimes recently received a secret message from an informant in the Armed Forces Special Operations Division (AFSOD) of the Indian Armed Forces. It has become apparent that Major General A. K. Bera, Chief of AFSOD, has been worried sick since losing contact with the Special Forces Chameleon corps two days ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They have been trained in hiding too well. We will never find them,” said a passive aggressive lieutenant of the Garden Lizard corps who wished to remain unnamed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shri Shri Defense Baba has booked Delhi’s Jantar Mantar tonight for performing a special Girgit Safe Return Puja. Twenty thousand people are expected to arrive; social distancing protocols will not be enforced. BlackMyShow.com too has run out of tickets. Anjaanpur MLA Chota Hero has asked people to step out of their homes and fire crackers in the street at eight o’ clock tomorrow so that the lost men can hear our support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barrister Sunil Prabhakar has filed a PIL against the Delhi government for allowing such frivolous and misleading events at Jantar Mantar. The Delhi government has in turn blamed the Central Government for allowing such events in their jurisdiction and threatened to go on a hunger strike in Jantar Mantar right after instead. However, they have promised to enforce social distancing in their hunger strike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AFSOD has called upon air-force special forces Cobra Corps and navy special forces Turtle Team for the rescue mission. The Chief has informed us that the thoughts and prayers sent towards their mission using whatsapp forwards and facebook posts are sure to give them a special edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are all reptiles. We stick together,” said a reinvigorated Maj. Gen. Bera. “And we perform best in the heat of battle.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/chameleon-corps-lost/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/chameleon-corps-lost/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Flawed experiment finds vegetarianism a farce</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;flawed-experiment-finds-vegetarianism-a-farce&quot;&gt;Flawed Experiment Finds Vegetarianism a Farce.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;bored-restaurateur-runs-experiment-prices-meat-lower-finds-no-takers-for-paneer-anymore&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bored restaurateur runs experiment. Prices meat lower. Finds no takers for paneer anymore.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shimoga, January 2021:&lt;/strong&gt; Vegetarianism, the consumption of products not involving slaughter of animals (without consent), is a practice followed by many. While many Indians consider it merely a way of life, there exist others who do it either to alleviate their guilty consciences of bringing harm to animals or to continue qualifying as a celebrity and staying in vogue. Some do it ‘cause their friends fangirl peta and force them to forego meat. But the final outcome is inevitable; such a friendship won’t last long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;K. Dharamgowda, a third generation restaurateur from Shimoga, Karnataka, is a connoisseur of food. The only thing that overshadows his love of food and wealth is his love of science. Drawn early into the family business after his father’s death, Dharamgowda was unable to stay in academia for long. His passion for science was as delectable as his ability for it was lacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was curious why certain people ate meat and certain didn’t. So he went ahead and priced all the non-vegetarian dishes lower than the vegetarian ones for a week. He told everyone of the change in prices but not the intention behind it. He had heard of “blind studies”. Throughout the week, there were no takers for veggies and paneer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ecstatic with his findings, Dharamgowda invited the local media for a press conference. He declared, “Vegetarianism is not real. People are miserly. It will go away with cheaper meat. This is the truth.” Asked about whether he would still sell his meat dishes at lower rates like before, he said, “No.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experts from the ministry of health and scientists from research institutions as well as industry have been at the forefront in acknowledging this pioneering work. Think-tanks and endowments have been formed to discuss, appreciate, and spread this pioneering indigenous work. Efforts are being made to put this finding into practice and government policy. Mr. Dharamgowda is expected to be honoured with a Padma award this Republic Day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/vegetarianism-farce/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/vegetarianism-farce/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Boy attempts suicide. Discovers autoerotic asphyxiation.</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;boy-attempts-suicide-discovers-autoerotic-asphyxiation&quot;&gt;Boy attempts suicide. Discovers autoerotic asphyxiation.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In an exclusive interview with the resident President of the Hedon’s Society, our correspondent, Ado Ink, discovers their novel recruitment and matchmaking strategies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 2021:&lt;/strong&gt; Early in the interview, Ms. Maramma Horishetti, President/Head Hedon, explains her discomfort with the leadership position, but that it is this edginess that compels her to discharge her duties well. In the early years of the society, in the 1960s, the society had trouble with leaders who enjoyed leading so much that they chose to forget what the society meant to its fellows. Since then, leaders who find pleasure with the power have been expelled and termed infidels and false hedons. Now, ironically, only fellows who do not enjoy leading are made Head Hedons, albeit only for a year; a sacrifice every hedon finds worthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does the society mean to its fellows? I asked her. She explained, albeit succinctly. We find hedonists, facilitate their pleasures, and teach them control, class, and, most significantly, charisma. We take them from being aberrant and wacky to idiosyncratic and eccentric. Many observe their transformation and while they become more accommodated to the drab dystopia outside, choose to find their family here. &lt;em&gt;We have grown from pleasure to pleasure.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the fellows, whom the outside world brands obsessive-compulsive, have helped make  functioning of the society smooth, cataloguing the variety of modern pleasures. Surprisingly, or rather unsurprisingly, the only members who are disappointed as a result of this are the fellows who love surprises. Well, actually, no. The murderers and the rapists also. But they are no longer members, so definitively, yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a minute of awkward silence, nervous clattering, and some frantic fake coughing outside the door, my nervousness slowly subsided. She comforted me with a tale of the thundering third Head Hedon who was the first to infiltrate the Eavesdroppers Anonymous, not that they knew of course, and had liberated many of the younglings. In his honour, the society still holds fortnightly sham secret meetings for the eavesdroppers to eavesdrop on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was now that I had discovered the trickery of Ms. Horishetti. She was no Sardar Patel when it came to leading (or extorting/blackmailing either), but she was a conversationalist of the superlative degree. She had tricked me and caused us to digress away from the boy ToI had termed “the boy who lived”. &lt;del&gt;Typical ToI. Couldn’t refrain from plagiarism. “pop culture” my ass.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How was the boy found? I emphasised. She had to concede. “Everyone sees us. Few notice us. Fewer still look for us. Scant seek us. We gather these remnant seekers and bring them here.” She assures me that I have seen them and when I discover my true pleasure I would discover them too. She also assures that none of their banner ads are annoying. Well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy was a young one, naught but nineteen years of age. Staying away from home hadn’t been pleasant to him. Nothing led to another nothing, and there he was trying to force stop his life. Fortunately, his noose gave him the most ecstatic experience he’d ever felt. He soon discovered the society and sought it. Ms. Horishetti tells me that in the past few years, the recruitment team has had tremendous success. With the spread of internet access, it has become easier to reach eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would the boy’s fate be now? I asked. The Head Hedon laughed out loud. She found my concern amusing. The boy hadn’t contracted a deadly disease. He had only learned something new about himself, a thing that was turning out to be latent in large numbers of the population now. She reckons this asphyxiation fixation to the Vespa fad of 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy has found himself a complementary mate at the society, one who is meek, but also particularly fancies choking others. Ms. Horishetti had picked her matchmaking chief from the board of Mensa. The Chief funds matching compatible people more fun than matching colourful sweets on increasingly smaller screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are exciting times, says the Head Hedon. The populace’s notion of normalcy is evolving. As eccentricities become more mundane, the society will become both omnipresent and absent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/hedon's-society/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/hedon's-society/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Salman Khan refuses to release movie in 2021; Says people have suffered enough</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;salman-khan-refuses-to-release-movie-in-2021-says-people-have-suffered-enough&quot;&gt;Salman Khan refuses to release movie in 2021; Says people have suffered enough&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;same-shahrukh-khan&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Same”: Shahrukh Khan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bollywood, January 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: With &lt;em&gt;Radhe&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Antim&lt;/em&gt; in post-production, Salman Khan appears to be waiting for people to get over their suffering and disease to release his movies. Rumours abound that even though his PR team suggested releasing the movies soon, pointing to the lack of taste being a symptom of COVID19 and not just a characteristic of his audience, Mr. Khan refused to act on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While A-list actors have decided to sit on their money and wait out the pandemic, tryhard B-list and C-list actors have turned to Youtube and Tiktok for work. “We cannot wait it out like them,” said a flustered Fardeen Khan. “My crack dealer is crawling up my ass for his money and I need to find work fast.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the Aurangabad Regional Head of the Salman Khan Fan Federation gathered two hundred supporters at the city centre to uncover a hundred posters of Salman Khan and poured milk on it to persuade him to release a new movie. “We are very sad that Bhai hasn’t released a movie in over a year. We want him to know that we are waiting,” said the Regional Head who wished to remain unnamed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a video of Mr. Khan leaked on Twitter yesterday, many Mumbai citizens rejoiced and turned out in the streets to celebrate the relief at not having to be hounded by blathering movie-goers. The increase in the density of people in the streets was quickly observed by the municipality and security forces were sent to detain the leaders of the crowd in order to fight the spread of COVID.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another set of protests broke out after the Film Crew Workers’ Union’s leaders met during the weekend. “By sheer numbers, the crew make up more of the film industry than the cast. And we are unhappy with this trend,” said an emotional Mr. Diaz, the union chief. “The actors can wait out the employment hiatuses in their mansions. We don’t have the luxury to do that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the union workers have also transitioned to working on Tiktok and Instagram Reels content. “The quality of content is really not that different,” said Cut Dada, an editor with over 15 years of experience in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Diaz and the union workers staged a protest and walked to Juhu with obscene placards aimed at “highbrow” actors. The Shiv Sena has claimed that this is not a protest about disgruntled workers and unemployment at all. They say the protest has been hijacked by anti-national elements and needs to be stopped immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Salman-Khan-says-no-movies/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Salman-Khan-says-no-movies/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>German man participates in book exchange. Receives 36 copies of Mein Kampf.</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;german-man-participates-in-book-exchange-receives-36-copies-of-mein-kampf-in-hebrew&quot;&gt;German man participates in book exchange. Receives 36 copies of Mein Kampf, in Hebrew.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Book Lovers Unite: Gift a book. I need six (may exceed) people, of any age or nationality, to participate in a book exchange. You only have to buy ONE book and send it to one person and you’ll receive 36 in return! Comment if you’re interested and I will inbox you the details. Also, please do it only if you will actually buy a book. This is not a prank.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;December 2020, Chinchpur: The popular book exchange scheme has been around for a few years now but it is still going strong, as witnessed by our editors who’ve since had to block a lot of people from their social media accounts. The “internet challenge” asks people to send one book, of their choice, to an address provided and promises 36 books in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jan Jung, a German baker, participated in the virtual book exchange last summer hoping to collect a few new and varied titles for his personal library. This week he received the last of his 36 copies of Mein Kampf. “It’s all a big practical joke,” he said. “Most of them are in scripts that I cannot read either. I’m not even sure if it is safe to donate them to the public library.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jan has become the butt of most jokes in his local pub this year. Although he presents a cool exterior, happy to be providing a good laugh to his mates, his wife agrees that this might have been a mistake. Pranks like this have been coming to the fore a lot more often now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sangeetha, a sociologist from Shiroda, Goa, participated in the internet book exchange while she was studying in university. Over the year, she received books like Salman Rushdie’s The Satanic Verses, S. K. Datta-Rey’s Smash and Grab, and several others which hold the distinction of being banned in India. Sangeetha has loved the collective idea all her book donors had and has made this the basis of her sociology thesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bharat, a rural school teacher from Chinchpur, Maharashtra, spent his school’s entire (albeit small) budget on this book exchange, hoping that this scheme will enable him to build a library for his village. But in five months, he has received a meagre 5 books, that too in Tamil and Malayalam, which no one in his village understands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popular investor and myth-buster, Mr. Bhaskar had very harsh words regarding the book exchange scheme. “This just exemplifies that not everyone who reads a lot of books is not utterly dumb,” he said. “People willingly participating in pyramid schemes masquerading as social experiments or online challenges epitomize the stupidity of human existence.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/pyramid-schemes-book-exchange-edition/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/pyramid-schemes-book-exchange-edition/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finland Public Schools introduce 'Revolution 2020'</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;finland-public-schools-introduce-revolution-2020&quot;&gt;Finland Public Schools introduce ‘Revolution 2020’&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;all-public-middle-school-kids-to-study-assorted-works-by-chetan-bhagat-germany-switzerland-to-follow-finn-lead&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;All public middle-school kids to study assorted works by Chetan Bhagat. Germany, Switzerland to follow Finn lead.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helsinki, December 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: Schools are arguably the most effective means of enacting the aims of integration. Passages from seminal works such as ‘Five Point Someone’ and ‘Two States’ have caught the imagination of the education system in Finland. Many ‘sayings and teachings’ from such spiritual Indian scriptures are incorporated now in the Finland School System with the aim of making world education compulsory starting from 5th grade onwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move comes after the Finnish government received oodles of praise from the Indian Hindu Community for their adoption of the Bhagavad Gita into their curriculum back in 2017. In the annual report published by the Association for International Hindu Cooperation and Propagation (AIHCP) in 2019, Finland received a 74/100, or a B+, for their commitment to maintaining and spreading the ideas of Hinduism and Indian culture, the highest score for a non Indian country and a higher score than the governments of many Indian states such as Kerala and West Bengal. A source at the AIHCP has confirmed that Finland’s score is set to increase in the 2020 report, placing it neck and neck with the score of the Gujarat government (88), and behind only the Uttar Pradesh government (95) and the Indian central government (92).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Finn Indians not only tend to perform better than other minority groups in schools, they also appear to integrate at a faster rate than other ‘non-Western’ immigrant groups,” says an unrelated Mr. Bhagat, leader of the Finn East India Company. “Partly this is because of shared characteristics with Finn society, as social aspirations among Finn Indians are consistently mediocre, and in general their orientation is towards the lamestream culture.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Finnish Ministry of Education and Culture conducted thorough research into different cultures and literatures and found Indian the most appropriate. Ms. Sini Makkanen, a representative of the ministry explains, “Chetan Bhagat’s works helps buffer the gap between Aesop’s fables and Charles Dickens.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She adds, “The forced sex scenes also make kids automatically averse to forced sex. One stone, Two birds. The kids don’t like this expression. We might lighten up on the Buddhism in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, a Gujarat university introduces a six-month certificate course in Astrology and Vaastu, and plans to allow diploma holders to pursue two year PhDs as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Chetan-Bhagat-in-school-curriculum/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Chetan-Bhagat-in-school-curriculum/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>China refuses to fight war citing social distancing; Suggests CoD tournament instead</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;china-refuses-to-fight-war-citing-social-distancing-suggests-call-of-duty-tournament-instead&quot;&gt;China refuses to fight war citing social distancing, suggests Call of Duty tournament instead.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;csgo-players-outraged-claim-their-zombie-mods-better&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;CS:GO players outraged; claim their Zombie mods better.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Delhi, July 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: Diplomatic talks with China have taken a turn for the new. In an unprecedented move, China has called for a ceasefire. India has a significantly higher number of Covid19 active cases. Chinese officials have claimed that this has forced their hand to call for distancing their soldiers from the infection. “India is chock full of Covid19 infection. We cannot allow our soldiers to face such dangers,” said a diplomat from Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the intervening period, while the pandemic subsides, China is proposing a Call of Duty Battle Royale style tournament where the winner takes all. As a display of its generosity, it has agreed to play the first tournament for 10 km of its own territory in the Aksai Chin territory of Kashmir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the Indian diplomats have claimed this as a victory for India and hailed the current ruling central government as the best in history, the military top brass are not amused. “No. No. We can’t agree to that”, said General Thimayya, Chief of the Defence Staff. “They are bound to use aimbot hacks. Cheating is in their nature.” The Chinese spokesperson was unavailable for comment on the accusations of cheating as it was a Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Indian players have been griping that all their gaming equipment were made in China. They are now worried that if they were to use them against the Chinese teams, their gear could get remotely deactivated. The Indian Brotherhood of Gamers (IBG) has now moved to support the Make in India movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Majority of our hacks came from our Chinese comrades [n-sic]. But, now I’m not sure if we’ll be able to get the latest updates. Our indigenous hackers specialize in phishing. They don’t help us gaming folks,” tweeted one disgruntled gamer, @hackislife69420.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an exclusive interview with Rohit Ambani, India’s unanimous best gamer, we learn about how these developments have changed the gaming scene. “Yes. It’s all changing. We’re being forced to learn how to deal with game mechanics without the hacks. In light of this new information, my team has pioneeringly (sic) actually started practising. We have been frantically trying to get good.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing the opportunity to enter another market, Indian conglomerate Jio has offered to refurbish, overhaul, and technologise Mumbai’s Wankhede Stadium for the e-sport and supply the entire area with free electricity and high-speed fiber internet. They propose to rebrand it Jio Stadium. Also, in lieu of new partnerships, starting September, with Jio subscriptions of over INR400, customers can avail INR100 Steam gift cards.^&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;^Disclosure: We are not sponsored by Jio. We would like to though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*n-sic=not sic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/china-refuses-to-war/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/china-refuses-to-war/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mainland China in hot soup; Zomato rating down to 1.3.</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;mainland-china-in-hot-soup-zomato-rating-down-to-13&quot;&gt;Mainland China In Hot Soup, Zomato Rating Down to 1.3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;beijing-alleges-a-resurgence-of-mccarthyism&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Beijing alleges a resurgence of McCarthyism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hyderabad, August 2020:&lt;/strong&gt; Angad Chatterjee, founder and chairman of Speciality Restaurants Ltd., Mainland China’s holding company was caught unawares by the review bombing. “My restaurants and my employees are all 100% Indian,” Mr. Chatterjee pleads to the masses on twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an exclusive interview with The Hindustan Grimes, Mr. Chatterjee griped about the activism. “Me, my company, my employees are all Indian. All the ingredients we use are Indian. Even our recipes are Indian, they only sound like they are Chinese. All this internet activism is very bad for indigenous businesses like ours.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The upper management has now made it a policy to cover up all mention of the word ‘China’ and its variants on shop-fronts, hoardings, banners, posters, and menu-cards, with black fabric or paint. This was in direct response to the violent incident that took place in Hyderabad last week. “Four days ago, one of our restaurant managers was beaten up by gang of nationalist hooligans. Our policy changes came into effect nationally three days ago. We cannot endanger our employees any further.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The district police has been investigating the matter. Inspector Singham, the officer-in-charge has stated that the investigation is running into some friction. The community has been hiding the suspects and are not cooperating with the police.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days ago, the Indian Intelligence Bureau intercepted coded messages and was able to learn of Chinese sympathisers disguising as Mainland China employees. This has led to a series of arrests simultaneously on all Mainland China premises across the country. “We have reliable information that Mainland China was a cover for multiple sleeper cells. We did not fall for their double bluff,” said Mr. Kumar, director of the IB. “They will be fools to think we cannot fight the war on two fronts. We will fight both on the outside and the inside.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Chinese spokesperson has responded on Twitter claiming this an act of McCarthyism. “They are making accusations of subversion and treason without proper regard for evidence. #India merely issued these arrests to justify itself. It cannot give one example of Indian citizens arbitrarily detained in China. Many Chinese citizens are searched, harassed, or monitored in India without cause. The ghost of #McCarthyism is rising from the dead.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When twitterati reminded him that the people arrested were Indian citizens, he retracted his earlier message and tweeted, “Understandable. Have a great day.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Mainland-China-Un-stonks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Mainland-China-Un-stonks/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Facing extreme dearth, Airlines consider offering Pay Now, Fly WheNever</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;facing-extreme-dearth-airlines-consider-offering-pay-now-fly-whenever&quot;&gt;Facing extreme dearth, Airlines consider offering Pay Now, Fly WheNever^&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;among-other-measures-air-india-hires-uber-consultants-asks-pilots-to-take-care-of-their-own-parking-and-fuel-introduces-pilot-ratings&quot;&gt;Among other measures, Air India hires Uber consultants; asks pilots to take care of their own parking and fuel; introduces pilot ratings.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mumbai, July 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: The pandemic has grounded all domestic flights for over three months now forcing the entire industry to a halt. We queried the Airport Authority of India about what they were doing to alleviate the situation for the severely depressurising airlines, and they told us off firmly: “This is how capitalism works. If you cannot sustain yourselves, you perish.” They also added that they wouldn’t be paying any more than scrapyard prices for their planes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Air Traffic Controls from 5 metro cities across India have come together to organise a multiplayer ATC simulator tournament. After spending two months relieved that their government jobs will neither terminate nor pay any lesser, they’ve now sought to busy themselves. While the AAI maintains that this is only to keep their employees ready for resumption, the crash fest during the match between the Kolkata and Chennai teams says otherwise. “Yesterday some kids from Kota broke into our servers and schooled my boss,” said Ali, a junior executive at Mumbai ATC, “it was the most impressive work I’ve ever seen. We have asked the defence staff to include ATC tournaments in this and subsequent wars with China.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two chefs making all the overpriced in-flight food domestically have been rehabilitated successfully. Speeding down empty roads in structurally safe vehicles delivering food is making them feel right at home. However, they did not appreciate the transition as much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pandemic has affected not just the industry but some of the executives’ personal lives too. Mr. Hawa, CEO of Udanchoo Airlines hasn’t been able to see his second family in Delhi ever since all his flights were grounded. “Meeting my air hostesses online just isn’t the same,” adds his rival, Mr. Hawai of Airlines India grumblingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;^Hopefully. #Offers invalid if we declare bankruptcy&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/thegrimes/Airlines-Campaign/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegrimes/Airlines-Campaign/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Winter of Travelling : Partie Un</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Disclaimer :&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt; I'm not a Saarang volun&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;teer / coordin&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;ator / organiser.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I took &quot;Live life large&quot; a bit too seriously last sem. Made a bunch of huge plans for the winter, one of which was AIESEC programs, got selected, but then everything crumbled back to the earth. I was free.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;My first instinct after my last endsem paper was to sleep. Eventually, I &lt;i&gt;did&lt;/i&gt; wake up. And made my way to Mahabalipuram with 9 mates for the very first time together.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The start of the one day trip was of very typical fashion. We got delayed. It was nearly nine, an hour late from our planned departure, and we were waiting for the ever-busy, Yellow Pages, at the bus stop. He turned up, which in itself was a surprise for us; how had he made time for this!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-3BKym1Xkc_U/Wl7vFSDZFGI/AAAAAAAAEgg/vMdUHslbadgC_U3Ul0kHqVXHW8SX-5HFgCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20171123_173851617-ANIMATION.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;972&quot; data-original-width=&quot;730&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-3BKym1Xkc_U/Wl7vFSDZFGI/AAAAAAAAEgg/vMdUHslbadgC_U3Ul0kHqVXHW8SX-5HFgCLcBGAs/s640/IMG_20171123_173851617-ANIMATION.gif&quot; style=&quot;cursor: move;&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Fun is an understatement&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;We took out bus passes for an entire day's travel and reached the tranquility of Mahabs only when the Sun was already high up in the sky. The tranquility was crushed by a bunch or rather a horde of middle school kids who I imagine had gotten out of school in pursuit of mischief.. Understated. Understandable. They didn't pull in all our attention though. Mischief was on our agenda too and unlike the poor kids, we didn't have overseers!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That day, we learned the Sun was hotter than our Maami and hence had to buy a hat. It didn't stay long though. All of us wanted the shade, &lt;i&gt;and look funny&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our first &lt;i&gt;planned &lt;/i&gt;visit was a lighthouse for which we had to go via a rock temple on top of a huge cliff face. That did not stop KD though, he climbed up the steep face&amp;nbsp; with ease. Monkey see, monkey do. #Beach almost fell back as KD helped him up. The others and I on the other hand chose to take stairs cut in the rock a bit ahead.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;4pointer was with us. So photos and profiles were going to be obvious. Everyone was taking everyone else's pictures. It is silly how we were posing and jumping around, but what did we have to lose. It was fun. And if you were wondering, we did climb atop the lighthouse.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then we made our way to the famous Krishna's Butterball, the boulder that stands atop a not-too-steep yet slippery surface of rock and miraculously stays there. We were so dehydrated by the Sun, the rock didn't even amaze us initially. Our only motivation to climb up it was there was shade under the rock. I was among the last ones to be going up, and I began to lose my grip. Gopi tried hard to keep up from falling, but I had other ideas. I slipped and slid down the face of the humongous rock structure. Except the ridiculously difficult stain I had to remove from my pants, all was okay. I did rekindle everyone else's juvenescence and&amp;nbsp; to the age old time tested activity of sliding down smooth surfaces. In short, we slid down. &lt;i&gt;For a fun video of us sliding down the rock, text me.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then we made our way to the beach and to food, The restaurant was literally on the beach. Catering often to the foreign crowd, most of the food on the menu was either miserable or overpriced. But we were near the sea. All would be okay.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-wW7hUycyg9k/WmJV_0lISBI/AAAAAAAAEjg/lTS1JJmtt1w22fueWn5kA38QG6ZTJB5uQCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_2523.JPG&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1067&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;265&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-wW7hUycyg9k/WmJV_0lISBI/AAAAAAAAEjg/lTS1JJmtt1w22fueWn5kA38QG6ZTJB5uQCLcBGAs/s400/IMG_2523.JPG&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;We walked along the beach to the rocky part which was the highlight of my day. I felt so much at ease there that I didn't even take a good picture of it. If you've never been there, it's time to go now. It's a lovely place to lie down, feel the time slowing down with the calming reverberation of the eternal waters hitting the rocks, and write poetry.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-iefWtO3LEmM/WmJjytFdPQI/AAAAAAAAEjw/yCRzEVG3V9oz3xr1qJ_In7blBl413tYIgCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_2481.JPG&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1067&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;213&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-iefWtO3LEmM/WmJjytFdPQI/AAAAAAAAEjw/yCRzEVG3V9oz3xr1qJ_In7blBl413tYIgCLcBGAs/s320/IMG_2481.JPG&quot; title=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;This was the hat BTW&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;We saw the Sun go down toward the nature-struck eroded rock temple very appropriately and simple named the Shore temple. And then we were on our way back. Tired. And planning about where to go the next time.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;goog_155595180&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;goog_155595181&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Check back here tomorrow for a bunch of free verse. Bye.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 03:11:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/a-winter-of-travelling-partie-un/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/a-winter-of-travelling-partie-un/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>a Hit and a Miss : Saarang '18</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.saarang.org/images/icons/home.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;325&quot; data-original-width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;161&quot; src=&quot;https://www.saarang.org/images/icons/home.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This is my story of Saarang '18.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;(Correction: This was supposed to be my story of Saarang '18. There's not much to say though.)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My Saarang primarily involved just 4 places, CRC, Bed, Food, and lounging around KV grounds in the night. The lounging around involved a lot more compulsive affairs, but that's a story for another time.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;6 quizzes over 4 days. Shamelessly honest I shall be. I neither set any nor did I make finals. Yet my newly&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;re&lt;/i&gt;founded quiz enthusiasm is at an all-time high. I sat through the lone wolf quiz which ran through the whole of the night, describing which with just interesting or good would be an insult. The opinion is obviously biased. I'm into the general idea of general quizzes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Having been introduced to the way of the quizzer only after coming to insti last year was a radically novel thing to me. The enthu phase was exhilarating. I had Faidh with me to accompany me to the quizzes. The high was when Govind, Rajat, and I placed second in a Shaastra quiz, but then it plunged pretty low pretty slow. I was behind on a lot of stuff. I was lurking in the shadows, just testing my hand at it again and again. Then there was a blip, a good one, when I went to NIT Trichy's Festember in September.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The sudden resurgence came with me prepping for &lt;i&gt;the biggest fest in&amp;nbsp;Asia&lt;/i&gt;( I still have no clue why they keep claiming that), IIT Bombay's Mood Indigo. The trip (pun intended) continued onto Inter IIT cultural meet in IIT Kanpur, only the second year the event has happened at all. I skipped Shaastra '18 for no apparent reason. I just wanted to return home and that feeling justifies everything for me. Then comes the start of the post, Saarang '18. I didn't place anywhere, yet the confidence is strong and the enthu is just bubbling to blow over.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That was a long digression from what I was intending to write. But, then again, I haven't written in a while. Let fingers lead the mind as instinct leads the wolf.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Very appropriately, my experience of Saarang was only as short as this post. (&lt;i&gt;And included as much digression&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 11:49:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/a-hit-and-miss-saarang-18/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/a-hit-and-miss-saarang-18/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Old Man's​ Guide to the GalacSea</title>
        <description>&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Wait! What? I seem to have jumbled up my last two reads. Two very different genres. Easy guess. The Old Man and the Sea by Earnest Hemingway, and then the Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy by Douglas Adams. You'd have known this sooner had you read my last post too. &lt;br&gt;*Gallic shrug*&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The Old Man's character wasn't&amp;#8203; easy to connect with initially, neither was Manolin, the eager young kid who tries to help. I never did get how old or how young Manolin really was; old enough to buy alcohol yet young enough to run small errands with no clashing pride or ego. But, as the story is built, one just gets pulled into the sea. The feat performed itself appears superhuman, &lt;u&gt;but&lt;/u&gt; doesn't merely elicit ephemeral emotions. As Santiago fights a battle for survival, he is suddenly inundated with prizes that could have been highlights on their own, but had to be let go for the ultimate one. As time passed, I could see myself cheering for him, hoping for something good to happen to Santiago. I knew something tragic could happen too. I prepared for it. A death. But, the eventual turn of events are even more tragic than the protagonist's death itself. Life goes on for us, as it did for Santiago too, but this story will be remembered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;After the sadness of the novella, I found on my Kindle a book I've been wanting to read for a long time. There's no real reason wh&lt;i&gt;i&lt;/i&gt; I hadn't read it yet. I'd heard of its awesomeness and it didn't disappoint. It was time to read H2G2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;If I was a BuzzFeed writer, I would now be writing &quot;42 Reasons Why You Should R&lt;i&gt;ead The &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Hitchhiker's&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt; Guide&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt; to&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt; the Gal&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;axy&quot;&lt;/i&gt;. As much cringy as it may sound, I wouldn't regret it. The plot, the characters, the infinite improbability with which science has been played, are all great, but my favourite aspect was the narration, the writing style itself. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The way Adams can keep you reading arbitrarily placed sets characters which make no sense in or out of context makes me wonder if anyone else will ever be able to duplicate such madness. Take this for example: &lt;br&gt;&quot;&lt;i&gt;One of Zaphod's heads looked away. The other one looked round to see what the first was looking at, but it wa&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;sn't looking at anything very much.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;And if you were wondering, it sounds just as balderdash even when it'&lt;i&gt;s &lt;/i&gt;read in context.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I loved H2G2 so much, it's no surprise what I'm going to read next. &lt;u&gt;The&lt;/u&gt; Restaurant at the End of the Universe. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Below is an excerpt from H2G2, which also happens to be my favourite passage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;Stress and nervous tension are now serious social problems in all parts of the Galaxy, and it is in order that this situation should not be in any way exacerbated that the following facts will now be revealed in advance.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The planet in question is in fact the legendary Magrathea. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The deadly missile attack shortly to be launched by an ancient automatic defense system will result merely in the breakage of three coffee cups and a mouse cage, the bruising of somebody&amp;#8217;s upper arm, and the untimely creation and sudden demise of a bowl of petunias and an innocent sperm whale.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;In order that some sense of mystery should still be preserved, no revelation will yet be made concerning whose upper arm sustains the bruise. This fact may safely be made the subject of suspense since it is of no significance whatsoever.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 23:34:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/old-man-guide-to-galacsea/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/old-man-guide-to-galacsea/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Resolutions bent</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-qyhUiufSQ4k/WlOE_QEq5lI/AAAAAAAAEdQ/VSN6qTb8f4gh5h1c3E93_OH4ophHW4YIgCKgBGAs/s1600/Screenshot_20180108-193246.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;274&quot; data-original-width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;151&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-qyhUiufSQ4k/WlOE_QEq5lI/AAAAAAAAEdQ/VSN6qTb8f4gh5h1c3E93_OH4ophHW4YIgCKgBGAs/s400/Screenshot_20180108-193246.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;Avery Tolar: Do you think l'm talking about breaking the law?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;Mitch McDeere: No, I'm just trying to figure out how far you want it bent.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;Avery Tolar: As far as you can without breaking it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;~ An excerpt from the Tom Cruise starrer, &quot;The Firm&quot;, based on the novel by John Grisham.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Well, I agree that's a lame excuse for not posting anything for the past three days, but I &lt;i&gt;did&lt;/i&gt; write the resolution myself, and nowhere did I mention that I have to post one daily. So &lt;i&gt;technically&lt;/i&gt;, no resolution broken.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;As my winter vacations come to an end, I have suddenly re-indulged in books. It happened towards the end of the recent summer vacations too. A book reading spree. Proud. During the end of summer, it was the Hunger Games trilogy, and the entire Harry Potter series (&lt;i&gt;the initial seven&lt;/i&gt;), and maybe one by John Grisham. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;This time it's novellas. The Metamorphosis by Franz Kafka. The Old Man and the Sea by Ernest Hemingway (which is a very moving &lt;u&gt;story&lt;/u&gt;; more about it later). And now I'm reading The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy by Douglas Adams. H2G2 is a very fun read.&amp;nbsp; I'm still only halfway through it but the narration is done too well to be not talked about, specially the way he diffuses the tension of suspense. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I need to leave now. &lt;br /&gt;Deep Thought's seven and a half million years are almost up.&lt;br /&gt;Check in tomorrow for more.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 20:21:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/resolutions-bent/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/resolutions-bent/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Room</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;I did nothing interesting yesterday or today, unless you consider getting into a crowded fast local with an overloaded backpack an event to write about. Okay, one can. I won't. So, today I've taken up the task to imagine and describe a room and see where it takes me.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Darkness shrouds the room. It is past sundown. The phosphorescent stars on the ceiling had grown old and glimmered only faintly to showcase the lax attempt to form accurate constellations. Tiny weak beams of orange from the street lights try to battle through the translucent blue curtains guarding the narrow ceiling-to-floor glass windows, creating a glow that was neither orange nor blue but a hue in between. The colour of the walls was indiscernible, indistinguishable among pale white, yellow or a shade of pink.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The clock's ticking grows louder as more light shining off of it reaches me. It is seven o clock. Slowly my eyes adjust to the darkness. I soak in more as I get up off my bed. On the far wall is the almirah, by far the oldest thing in the room, still as sleek as it was a decade ago when I those drawings of cartoons on it. Faded and weird in retrospect, the cheetos stickers on the almirah mirror are peeling off. The rest of the wall is full of framed pictures of me arranged chronologically in a stairway fashion going upward to the right. The pictures are fuzzy, the sort that was common until point and shoot digital cameras became more common. To my left was the balcony with the blue curtains. The small gap in the fixture had begun to make more noise as the wind blew inward. The room was on the second floor. The wind unavoidable. In the right side of the room is a 90s style ornate dressing table mimicking a Victorian era one, but with all the modern functionality, a 5 foot high mirror etched in the corners with flowery designs, and half a dozen drawers and cabinets. This was perfectly in sync with the aura created by the wooden queen sized bed showcasing early Indian school workmanship, that took up nearly half the room.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Right beside me was the most incompatible thing in the room, my study desk. The lamp on it stooped over just as I always eventually do as I work. The stack of books on it rose a mighty 2 feet. Torts, Penal Code, Personal law, Criminology, a lot of subjects were to be read. The clear workspace was an aberration though; my backpack had been neatly placed beside the desk. On the table was a ceramic dish covered by a plate, and a small note. It was my mother's handwriting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&quot;There's khichidi in the bowl. Finish it. I've gone to get bread.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 23:57:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/a-room/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/a-room/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kafka on the Fore(brain)</title>
        <description>&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The whole of my second day of the year was spent in a small train compartment among cold struck old men, young men intensely watching arbitrary dramatic movies on their phones, teenagers playing cheesy party songs on Bluetooth speakers, and two very touchy men sharing a side berth, who also happened to be small scale thieves. The teen was too careless with his phone though. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I had a good amount of food packed for lunch and dinner, courtesy of my lovely hosts at Kanpur. Hence, I was well set to spend my whole journey confined to an area not more than 20 square feet. (Le physics nerd, don't calculate the strip of land I covered due to the motion of the train.) Then, one thing struck me. Boredom. Reading up on Renaissance Art didn't help. So I did what every exciting young college kid does, I opened a novella.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Franz Kafka's The Metamorphosis is a short read packed with the absurdity that gave the world the word &quot;kafkaesque.&quot; There is no thriller climax expectation or an impending cliffhanger, but he does place the bomb under the table with the very first page. It's a pageturner. The plot essentially starts with the protagonist, Gregor Samsa, morphing into an insect, but I understood the true metamorphosis to be that of his family afterward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The protagonist turning into an insect is absurd, exactly what Kafka is known for. His mind is still human, but incomprehensible for the rest. After the initial scare, they start seeing him as a part of the family and try to take care of him yet not having the stomach to see his body, but soon he is just seen to be a burden. The transformation in Gregor's sister is particularly remarkable. She goes from crying for her brother's wellbeing, feeding him, and cleaning up on him to blaming him for the misfortunes befalling her family and thinking his death as the sole solution. I'd call her transformation &lt;i&gt;the metamorphosis&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Kafka hit me on another level though. How long does it really take for a person to morph into a pest? How long will someone take care of me with no explicit gratitude? How long with no expectations? Suspicion creeps up soon. Regret follows. Eventually, pest control. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;If only I could run off to obscurity and find answers for myself.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/kafka-on-forebrain/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/kafka-on-forebrain/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Some Stereotypes Are Justified</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Ever&lt;/u&gt; heard of the old Chuck Norris-esqe joke about Rajnikanth painting the Red Fort red with his spit? Well, travel to Kanpur and you'll realise that's​ quite possible.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The start was indicative enough. I took a train from Mumbai to Kanpur, and every 10 minutes there'd be someone screaming brands of pan masala, hawking tobacco. Every 10 minutes. It was hard enough for this damned memory device to not remember all the names. I'm not gonna recite them here though.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;As it turned out, I was on the banks of river Ganga on the first day of the year, and not only did it confirm that tobacco is commonplace here, considering that there were red spit marks on the bank's wet silt as well, but also that the Ganga is really filthy. _Kanpur teri Ganga maili_. But that didn't stop that guy from nearly skinny dipping into thigh high waters. Or from common people buying containers and filling up. I guess rotting food, flowers, and paper are just the norm.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Some visibility still persists in this dense fog. My Kanpuriya host tells me frequent visits by the Chief Minister, Yogi Adityanath, has improved the roads a lot; also persistent are the people's erratic error-prone driving habits. Also, courtesy of the Yogi, was a renewed and beautiful Nana Sahib's fort and an uprising of 1857 memorial. I might as well thrown in the numismatic and philately museum it, depicting the history of Kanpur, and the evolution of currency and stamps of India and the world.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;But the most amusing thing was this sign we found in the premises of the fort.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-BQOSHpku46M/WktYorsgG3I/AAAAAAAAERs/VKOjrFOPcRMMPhHGL3yuoshBmFpHsqE6QCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20180101_124202946.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;900&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-BQOSHpku46M/WktYorsgG3I/AAAAAAAAERs/VKOjrFOPcRMMPhHGL3yuoshBmFpHsqE6QCLcBGAs/s640/IMG_20180101_124202946.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Respecc. Always. Courtesy, Respect Women AC Restaurant&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cawnpore might have evolved to Kanpur, but the town and the inhabitants still remains the same. The old town feels are strong with this one.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 15:41:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/some-stereotypes-are-justified/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/some-stereotypes-are-justified/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cringe Post 1 : New Year's Resolutions</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;This past year has been a fine upward facing parabolic morale curve with the bottom appearing depressive and slow, but the end ramped up just right. As every other simple minded Bitcoin &lt;i&gt;speculator&lt;/i&gt; believes, &quot;It only goes up from here.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Let's get right &lt;i&gt;down&lt;/i&gt; to the purpose of this&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;humongously &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;purposeful&lt;/i&gt; post, my resolutions. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;There are a few things that I absolutely have to get done, like do a research intern in the summer, lead my team to a Gold at the iGEM Jamboree, keep posting to this blog everyday.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Then there are qualitative things that cannot be done on its own but need me to regularly and constructively work toward, say for example learn French enough to hold a conversation, place top 3 in a quiz (I'm going to Nihilant this year. So yayyyy!!), learn to play a harmonica.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Then there are tinier things that might just make a difference, like travelling (hopefully there'll be more posts about new places here), trekking (not very high hopes here), basketball and generally staying fit (don't judge me, everyone resolves to do this too), some lucid dreaming, some scriptwriting, and lastly, an ability to say NO.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Ending on a frequent yet inspiring quote by the Vijs' dog, Krishi, &quot;Woof!&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-NNhEwJWtQaw/WkpLjSMETuI/AAAAAAAAERY/E5UOqE99QdAROOfJLvx8iiqjFrr1bfDsgCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20180101_184550654.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1189&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-NNhEwJWtQaw/WkpLjSMETuI/AAAAAAAAERY/E5UOqE99QdAROOfJLvx8iiqjFrr1bfDsgCLcBGAs/s400/IMG_20180101_184550654.jpg&quot; width=&quot;297&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;(Wow! That &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a long resolution.)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 20:34:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/cringe-post-1-new-years-resolutions/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/cringe-post-1-new-years-resolutions/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My First Sonnet !!</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;My father never tells me what he thinks,&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;always keeps me in a shadow of doubt.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Clashes with him have put in some kinks,&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;but, I shall never forget that dividing bout.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I was worn out, I wanted to exit the cage.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Dumb, I didn't realize my action was so bold;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I had sparked the fire, Hades' rage,&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;resulting in indifference, so bare, so cold.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Neither condonance nor fury was in our genes,&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But two things were, snub and mime;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Even after the cooldown, none spilled the beans;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Our bond had lost the prime time.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I know, though he is not all sugar and honey,&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It is he who ensures my account has money.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;PS&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This is a work of Fiction.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;For more about Sonnets, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sonnet&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 20:47:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/my-first-sonnet/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/my-first-sonnet/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>To Commute and Not To Commute</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;For the past few days, pull in even the last semester, I was missing something; something that helped me realize and define who I was. Neither am I so inquisitive, nor as much unoccupied, to go on some random journey to rediscover myself. In the meantime, I was also out of shape, so I started going cycling in campus post dinner. That is when I found out what I was missing.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;For ten of the past twelve years, I've spent a minimum of one-and-a-half to two hours a day commuting to and from school. I always thought I was wasting a lot of time. But, now I see, the alone-time I spent commuting was the time that I cherish now. Although I may not remember exactly what all I've done on those rides back home, but I certainly got a lot of time to think about random things, and things that were not random at all. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;I used to stand right by the door, with the wind blowing into my hair; and on rainy days, mud spraying onto my white pair of pants, making an awesome design and tough stains. (Now that I wash my own clothes, I realize how troublesome that was.) Nevertheless, my school bus rides were awesome. I've sit up front, beside the driver, and put up annoying songs on the player at loud volumes. I've sit out back, waiting for the driver to speed through a speed breaker so that my head touches the roof. I've been bullied there (that was one stray incident), I've stood up for others, I've cracked stupid jokes, and had serious conversations. As much as I have grown up in school, I've matured on my rides there.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5521c1e4e4b03e7ee28138a7/t/5521dcaae4b0bf9fbff7e940/1428282541517/?format=750w&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5521c1e4e4b03e7ee28138a7/t/5521dcaae4b0bf9fbff7e940/1428282541517/?format=750w&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;266&quot; src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5521c1e4e4b03e7ee28138a7/t/5521dcaae4b0bf9fbff7e940/1428282541517/?format=750w&quot; title=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Yesternight, the dark asphalt and the more than fifty shades of green and brown around me were augmented by the light drizzle, making it a lot more memorable. I could feel the droplets land on my head and flow down my face. (I can still feel it as I sit under the AC, sneezing!) The best thing, though, was the solitude, my thoughts talking to me. Cycling my way through the campus is a way I choose not to lose anymore. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 14:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/to-commute-and-not-to-commute/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/to-commute-and-not-to-commute/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Popcorn</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;It tastes different today,&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;the small plentiful;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;No one beside me&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;to take a handful.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A wannabe recliner&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;in a theater afar&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;pushed me back&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;to me popcorn jar.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The popcorn is bitter,&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;and my friends too;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;salted with sorrow&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;and my sobbing through.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 20:45:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/popcorn/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/popcorn/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sun, Shade, and Skedaddle</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&quot;Am I chasing him or is he chasing me?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&quot;Both, I think&quot;, I say, interrupting her. She doesn't respond; typical Rama, just lost in her thoughts.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;The setting Sun was glistening in her amber eyes and the rays through the canopy of palm leaves danced on her tanned skin. Sands to the right. Sands to the left. Frothy waters at our feet and hush all over. We're reclining in the sands of Baina beach of Vasco da Gama, Goa, her right hand in my left and her mesmerizing beauty in my eyes. Her face still bore that worried look, nose twitching, lips tightening, and her hand running across her hollow right cheek. We came here an hour ago in search of a quantum of solace, ice candy sticks in hand. Our eyes met often. There was a lot to talk about, words tried hard to form sentences, but it was futile. The ice had melted away. The last rays of the Sun sparkled in her eyes, her amber eyes, eyes that weren't amber a few months ago, a time when I recognized this personality by a different face.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;I saw her for the first time in December, the month of raw partying and maniacal after-parties. I am a native of Goa, and a pretty famous one. I built the organized vehicle rental business out of the small unorganized bike shacks on the beaches. I had access to all parties. I felt her presence at one of those. It was Sunburn at Vagator beach. There, our eyes met. Her hazel eyes, chameleon eyes, brown for a moment, green the next. Her eyes were pulling me to her. It was not one sided though. She was checking me out, probably because I was a peg down and she was two. I was in the usual Goan attire - shorts and a loose tee - my gym-built muscles bulging through it. She looked stunning in the short blue jumpsuit, her untanned skin showing through; she hadn't been in Goa a long time. We talked. We danced. We screamed to the music together. I had been to every Sunburn in Goa, but this lady just took the experience a notch higher. We looked wild together, the music wilder, and the night the wildest I had experienced.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;The next morning, the blinding Sun was staring into my bedroom through the huge windows, staring at me and the woman in my arms. Rama hadn't woken up yet. I got up, toasted some bread and made a couple of omelettes. She woke up with a bad hangover. I had none. After it eased a bit, she started asking questions. 'Who are you?''What do you do?' and similar mumbo-jumbo. When it was my turn to ask, she had only one answer, &quot;Find it out yourself.&quot; She kissed me goodbye and left. I liked her attitude. She challenged me, Shlok Aurora. I had first set my foot in Goa fifteen years ago. But, it seems like I have lived my whole life here. It is my home now. One doesn't build an empire from scratch alone. I started from the bottom. I am nearly at the top. I had so many contacts that I only had to make a couple of calls to keep a track of my enigmatic eve. She was the mystery novel that I couldn't put down.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;I waited in the shadows for two days, then, one evening, the last evening of the year, I sat &amp;nbsp;down across her in a Portuguese coffee shop on the Central Street of Margao. She was pleasantly surprised, yet not completely astonished, as if to say, 'It took you long enough'. She only came to know about my prowess when the coffee shop manager told her about it. She was more than into me. I was more than into her. We spent the last evening of the year together, and hoped this company would last. We spent the next month like a couple of high school kids, spending time together at beaches and markets, and snogging and groping at every chance possible. We saw the Sun set at Baga, Calangute, Valsao, Baina and many other beaches, and shopped in the Saturday Night Market and Holiday Street. There wasn't a beach we had not visited. I was getting habituated to the clandestine rendezvous in the nights.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;Our relationship was getting more intimate. We had been to the Pilot Point once when she let me into her mind. The beautiful cliff had caught her eyes and opened her up. She told me that she had run away from her family in Indore, albeit with a lot of money. They were involved in the adulteration of just about everything, and she wanted no part of it. She was looking for a new life. She found me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;Something very strange had happened in the Goa Carnival the following month. We had fun at the parades and the EDM nights, had luscious meals and long nights. Then, one evening, she vanished. She completely disappeared from the radar. I couldn't find her anywhere. No network could catch her. I felt like I had lost her forever.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;Three months later, just when I had lost all hope of finding her, she came back. The call came late in the night. Her voice was soothing. She set up a meet for breakfast at the Japanese Garden in Mormugao, little did I know I was in for a shock. I couldn't recognize her even when she was right in front of me. Her face had changed, wholly. She had undergone a plastic surgery and she had to explain why.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;On that night in Chorao island when she had disappeared, she had become the victim of an acid attack. Her face was melting off when she was rescued by Reverend Paulo Clement. He admitted her in the emergency wards of Manipal Hospitals in Panjim. Later she moved to the Cosmetic Surgery Institute in Mumbai and had been there for the past three months. The only person who knew where she was was Reverend Clement, and he found no reason to contact me. One thing was still off; why had she not contacted me? But, this was not the time to ask such questions. She had been through a lot of trauma, and I didn't want to cause more of it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;The Surgeons in Mumbai had done a brilliant job on Rama. No one could recognize her by her face now. There was no sign of any acid attack on her face, but the scars were still fresh in her mind. She remembers how she was mugged outside the little Chorao village by a trio of petty thieves and left there to rot with the bruises. Then, she was found by a surreptitious masked man, who drugged her, toyed with her for a while, and then melted her face with acid. She still felt the burn sometimes, uncontrollable, painful, unbearable. However, she has no idea who that man was or what his motive was. She refuses to go to the police, and the only lead we have about this man is his physical description - tall, tanned skin tone, a weird clumsy walk, hoarse voice, and the strong odour of fish. There was another unique thing though, the symbol of a dagger in a lion's back on the mystery man's wrist.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;For the past few days, I had tried to ease the tension in her while I continued trying to trace that man in the background. The symbol that she had described belonged to an old biker gang in Benaulim, the Triumphant Triumphs. They were old, brash, and involved in a lot more than just biking. I smelled something bad but I didn't have a lot of information. Rama and I headed there the moment we got to know about it. The Triumphs were not very difficult to find but it was hard to extract information. Little did I know Rama was so resourceful. She managed to seduce a biker and learn about the whereabouts of a young man, who fit the right description. He was known to be vicious. His name was Sahay and he worked in a fisheries processing factory in Candolim. We spent the evening on Baina. She was scared if Sahay was onto us. I assured her that we would nab him the next day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;The chase for the man continued, but I was having excess baggage. As we neared the outskirts of Candolim, I noticed some goons from the biker gang following us, and no, they didn't appear like they were here to help us. Just as we got to the address we had, we were caught by the gang who overpowered us and took us in the abandoned factory we so comfortably had come to. We were handcuffed and thrown in a small room. The room was small, dimly-lit, with a single entry, and smelled of rotting fish. We had no way out. Things started getting more entangled. Rama was laughing like a woman possessed. I began shouting, &quot;What happened Rama?&quot; &quot;Why are you laughing?&quot; &quot;We're doomed.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;Rama spoke, suddenly in a very serious tone, &quot;We aren't doomed. You are.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&quot;What? You got us into this?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&quot;Yes, you swine. Don't you get it. You are a fool who got into our trap. There was no acid attack. It was all Sahay's plan. I was just trying to kill you, but Sahay schemed to extort some money while I was at it. Now, you pay or you die a slow and painful death. Now, you pay to die.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&quot;Kill me? Why..?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&quot;Why? You don't know the consequences of your acts, do you? While you were building your enterprise, you stepped on a lot of people. One of those unfortunate people was my brother. He was doing well with his bike shack, but you had to kill it. He got bankrupt. He was depressed for months, and he found only one escape: Suicide. While you were partying your ass off, I was mourning the death of my last blood relative. I vowed to avenge his death. My mourning ends with yours.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;Sahay was outside the room with his goons, listening to all this chatter. The task was nearly complete. He was in no hurry.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;I had heard enough. It was my turn now, &quot;I have two questions for you: Why are your hands still cuffed? And where is Sahay?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;She had no apparent answer for the first question. She vehemently called out for Sahay. She knew he was outside, but why hadn't he unlocked her yet. She couldn't stand the confidence in my voice or my stoic eyes. She sensed something was wrong.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;Sahay entered the room in a slow stride, trying to redo that weird walk, however he couldn't hold back. He gave me my deserved salute, unlocked my wrists, and helped me up. All Rama got was a sympathetic smile. She was furious. She started throwing questions, &quot;What is happening here?&quot; &quot;Shlok&quot; &quot;Sahay..!!&quot; &quot;What are you doing?&quot; Her voice was fading, as were her plans to kill me.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&quot;Shocked? Aw..! I expected more from you. You think I didn't know your true intentions? I knew who you were from the first day we met. You could never succeed in your mission. You think Sahay dropped into your path with a plan, on his own? No. I sent him.&quot; I turned to him, &quot;Why don't you introduce yourself?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;Sahay spoke, &quot;Rama, eh? Or should I call you Maria Ferrao? I am not Sahay. My name is Yashas Aurora, and Shlok here is my brother.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;She tried to say something, but words didn't form. We dropped her off at a lunatic home in Panjim.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;Yashas repeated himself, hopefully for the last time, &quot;Another wrong girl.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&quot;Next time, try to find me a girl who loves me, but doesn't want to kill me.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 18:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/sun-shade-and-skedaddle/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/sun-shade-and-skedaddle/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let Go</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Yesterday I took part in the Freshie Creative Writing Competition. There were seven prompts and lots of freedom. I chose to go with a story. Here it goes.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;LET GO&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The time on the dial read 6. The fuel levels had hit reserves. Arun also had a hunger pang of sorts after the early and hurried bunch. He had been driving for the past 8 hours at a stretch from the metropolis that we call Chennai. Early on, he had lost his way in the maze of toll roads, but the GPS managed to re-route him to the highway down south to Kanyakumari. There are a lot of things one can do in a free weekend, right after getting the first salary, in a new city, but getting out of the city was his first priority. At this moment though, he was on the desperate look out for a refill, for both himself and his rental car.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The last hour had put on show some serene scenery but no pitstops. Even the small old signboard indicating refreshments off the highway looked promising. He couldn't think of a better choice. He got off the highway and onto the dingy bumpy road that seemed to crave repairs for more than a decade. Dink, Donk. Tin - Tin. The old car was making weird noises. But lo and behold! A pitstop!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The place was huge. There were enough booths to cater to more than fifty vehicles, at any given time. And right across it was a long row of shops. It was one of those huge complexes found on the highways, except that it was not right on the highway and it was stranded. The high winds didn't affect anyone, because there was no one. There was only one light on; the departmental store. Arun was no Sherlock, but he had to ask around. He just parked the car somewhere in the dust and walked to the store.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The glass up front had turned opaque. The weather had taken its toll. It was evident. There were things that were not so evident though; the things that kept puzzling him; why the place was stranded? And why was this store open? He knocked. The door was open. He entered. The aisles were shabby and covered in dust. There was not much in the store. There was a middle-aged man behind the billing counter though. He had on him some rugged, casual clothes; a striped polo shirt, blue denims, and a sad face, which suddenly lit up with a smile.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Arun was accustomed to the &quot;Good Evening Sir. How may I help you?&quot; But to expect that here would be foolish. He did hear something though. The man said, &quot;Hi! Good to see another living soul around here. But, Sorry! We are closed!&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Arun did expect this. Yet, his nature prevented him from walking away. He had to know the story. Apparently, he was in no hurry. He began, &quot;Hi! I'm Arun. I was heading to Kanyakumari. Empty tanks made me take a detour.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&quot;Oh! I'm Shrinath. This was my father's plaza. But, we are out of business.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&quot;You seem to be worried about something. Are you alright? And what are you doing here anyway?&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&quot;I'm fine. Dad's memories bring me here.&quot; Shrinath was in a dilemma now. To speak or not to speak, or just to throw the man away. Rationality soon returned. He continued,&quot; I shouldn't bother you. Its a long story.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Shrinath appeared honest, innocuous, and in need of a talk. He looked more pathetic than the store's untouched-for-years arrangement. Arun could see this. He said softly, &quot;I am in no hurry.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Shrinath knew Arun was hungry. He was no mindreader. But, no one wants to speak to a stranger, not for free. He opened his tiffin box. There were a bunch of sandwiches in it; some with butter, some with jam, some with both.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&quot;Its not much. But, you can have these. I don't usually expect people here&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Arun was a polite human. Hunger made him do things. He grabbed one right off the bat and spoke, &quot;So, what's the story?&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&quot;It goes back ten years from now. My father had bought this plaza with expectations of making a fortune. The unusually low price for such a place did spook him. However he was too stubborn to let go of such a nice looking investment opportunity. He put all his savings in this. The old highway passed through here. The business was good. We were always busy. Cars lined up. Customers queued up. The orders piled up. We were in profits. Until, one day, the news cropped up. A bigger highway was coming up, and we were gonna be left behind.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Arun grabbed his second sandwich. Shrinath didn't mind. He had someone to speak to. He carried on, &quot;Three years passed in peace. Then, the new diversion was inaugurated. Business started falling. No one wanted to drive extra for anything, Only the loyal ones kept coming back. But, not for long. We cut down on jobs. We had to cut corners. We were scraping through.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&quot;One unfortunate day, my father had to start managing this shop himself, at the counter. We couldn't pay for an employee anymore. Then, the worst nightmare came true. There was an armed robbery by some novice thugs. I only came to know about it in the evening. I cannot describe the scene, nor what I feel. When the police had come, dad was still holding the cash register, with a gun shot in his back. He died in the shop. The business was already on its knees, that shot killed it too.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The piece of bread was buttered well, but he couldn't get it down his throat. Here was a man who had been through all the nightmares, and still remained stoic. Arun could only give his condolescences &amp;nbsp;He was shaken. He couldn't hear anymore of the story. He got up, gave a firm handshake, thanked Shrinath for the food, and left.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Even as he got on the highway, his mind was still in the shop. The last part of their conversation still kept ringing in his ears.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&quot;No one ever told him; he never let go.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;No one ever told him; they thought he must know.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;P.S.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;The last line was the prompt.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 00:15:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/let-go/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/let-go/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dates with the Death</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Yesterday I had been to the semester's first Inklings session, Writing Club's official meet. We met new people; introduced ourselves. The theme of the session was Narrative Styles. A few interesting prompts were put up to write on. I wrote the following piece of fiction. Guess the prompt will follow.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;Today is 31st of August. The anxiety has officially kicked in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I've known it for three years now. The device worked perfectly well to display the auspicious date, the date I am to die, but blew up in my face when it was to tell me the year; and blew down all my plans for the future like a wall of cards.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A thousand days have passed, yet I don't know what fun the Satan wants to have, killing me on the Fifth of September. Is it because I hated most of my teachers? Or that most of my students hate me now?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My death day is just a week away. The usual cycle has begun; the binge watching those same old shows, binge eating or shall I say, drowning in gravy, and listening to the old tunes till my ears go numb. I woke up yesterday in a puddle of melted ice cream; I don't know how much of it was from the tub and how much from my vessels. But, the most fun affair still remains freaking everyone out by throwing a death day party. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The first year was the worst. I expected to die peacefully as the clock hit twelve. I was waiting. The hour hand slowly moved to one, but there was no sign of my clandestine rendezvous with Death. The hour hand turned two rounds, but Death never turned up. I had spent all my savings, hoping Death will be faithful. I see it now. I was so naive. His was among the many laughs I had to painfully bear.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I've had three bouts with him, but no knockouts yet. Neither am I able to overcome that fear, nor do I succumb. Even shelling out resources to the psychotherapist has been of no help. The nerves seem to be getting closer every year. One of these years, I might just kill myself to prove my device's prophesy right. I guess, this is how all prophesies come true.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I believe I'm gonna die on a Fifth of September. Hopefully, my postmortem declares death due to natural causes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;The writing was followed by reading your piece out loud, and expecting some constructive criticism. Maybe because it was the first of many sessions, everyone just felt awestruck hearing others' stories and poems, and just praised. No one received any criticism. The session was welcoming. Oh! I almost forgot. The prompt read, 'You know your Death Date, but not the Year.'&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 10:59:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/dates-with-death/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/dates-with-death/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The time is now? The ground here?</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Its 9'o'clock in the night. The TV room is filled with overly excited cricket fans watching a T20 match between India and West Indies. The room can easily fit 50-60 people. I lie not; Right now there's no place to step in. I&amp;nbsp; just left and had to step over some feet to get back to my room. That's right, I'm not one of those fans who'll watch the whole match. So, I'm sitting in my room with a wireless keyboard in my lap and my roommate's laptop on the other side of the room.&lt;br /&gt;Right place? I don't know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have an assignment to complete, a tutorial to solve, programs to write for tomorrow's laboratory, and revise for the quizzes beginning Thursday. Listening to my roomie's mixed English-Hindi-Punjabi playlist, even I'm thinking , as much as you are, if not more, why I am typing this. There's a cricket match going on. I studied in the morning; Played badminton in the evening; Shouldn't I just shut down?&lt;br /&gt;Right time? I don't know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Looking inside, I feel like I've been living a dual life of sorts. Dreaming of a big future, of going to far away lands and doing elaborate things. A place, hypothetical presently, where I am no more thinking of the future, When I know what I want to do and am doing it. Only when I contrasted it with my present did I realize how much I am adjusting and scraping through everything. If we had to literally step into the next day everyday, I would spend the whole day thinking if I should, and eventually just step into it anyway, just so that I can think about what'll happen days later.&lt;br /&gt;Right situation? I don't know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 22:33:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/the-time-is-now-ground-here/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/the-time-is-now-ground-here/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weakened in the Weekends?</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Finally, I get a free weekend to tell you about my last few busy weekends. Since I am a hostel-resident, sweeping and cleaning the room, washing clothes, studying programming in C and going to the bank, before writing this still counts as a free weekend. The best thing about a weekend is that I can wake up at 9 and not worry about missing a class. However, by the time I reached the mess, all the hot dosas were gone and I had to content myself with butter toasts.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The story of my weekends begins on Friday, the 22th of July. I was still in Belgaum. I would be in Chennai, for just the second time in my life, in 3 days. I had to buy things. I had to pack things. I was in a frenzy. I even had to meet my friends, for I wouldn't meet them in another 6 months. Though I didn't buy everything nor pack them properly, I did meet my friends that day. I had to leave home on Saturday. Even until two hours before my estimated time of departure, I wasn't sure of what I would take and what I'd leave behind. Dad and I did leave on time and reached Chennai on Sunday afternoon. The frenzy hadn't died just yet. I bought shoes and other stuff. The next day, we visited the campus that would be my home for the next 5 years; cleaned the room, set it up, bought a set of mattress and pillow, and awaited the orientations that would follow throughout the week. And for a fact, I still didn't know who my roommate was. (That is a story for another time)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;IITM has a five day week, with Saturdays and Sundays off. But, I was wrong to expect that the weekend will be uneventful. On Saturday, the 30th, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mitr.iitm.ac.in/main/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sathi &lt;/a&gt;had organized a Treasure Hunt for us Freshies. We were divided into groups of 20, and given 18 clues that led to different places in our campus. We had to decipher the clue, go to the place, and take a group selfie there with at least 10 of us in the frame. Our team did manage to decipher the clues and complete the task, but it was tiring running and cycling for 5-10 kilometres around the campus. Surprisingly, the purpose of the Treasure Hunt was different altogether, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://mitr.iitm.ac.in/main/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sathi&lt;/a&gt; succeeded in their purpose. At the end of the day, I had many new friends and new many of the places on campus.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-CN63NEFya8c/V7g3Ae1kX2I/AAAAAAAAAJw/zIIjbe3IVTIPAawL7CCh9uqh3owjhOn0ACK4B/s1600/IMG-20160729-WA0000.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-CN63NEFya8c/V7g3Ae1kX2I/AAAAAAAAAJw/zIIjbe3IVTIPAawL7CCh9uqh3owjhOn0ACK4B/s400/IMG-20160729-WA0000.jpg&quot; width=&quot;282&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iYznznP9Vyk/V7iRmWmSqxI/AAAAAAAAAJ8/G9v353yjSaAfgEhGJAzb9SLNHGw82aEbgCLcB/s1600/IMG-20160820-WA0002.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iYznznP9Vyk/V7iRmWmSqxI/AAAAAAAAAJ8/G9v353yjSaAfgEhGJAzb9SLNHGw82aEbgCLcB/s400/IMG-20160820-WA0002.jpg&quot; width=&quot;303&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;i&gt;The clues were interesting. For example, the first&amp;nbsp; clue was 'CULT without a cup.' In insti, cup stands for U grade (fail). This led to CLT or the Central Lecture Theater.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That night, I also watched my first movie, X-MEN: Apocalypse, in the Open Air Theater, in the rain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Next Friday and Saturday, we were given an introduction to all the cultural clubs on campus at the Club Weekender. We were introduced to the following clubs, in no particular order; thespian, quiz, writing, word games, music, media, choreo, fine arts, comedy, oratory, the fifth estate, and informals clubs. Naturally, I was attracted to quiz, word games, and writing clubs. We had buzzer rounds and I won a few munches! Then we had some fun at the word games club. We played games like Russian Doll. In the end, I reached the writing club, and that is where I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://adityajeevannavar.blogspot.in/2016/08/corners.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;corners&lt;/a&gt;, and began blogging again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There were many orientations in the week, but last weekend was quite insignificant. The only big thing I did last weekend was make the plan for this piece. Today, we did a lot more. In the evening, we had a session by Shastra 2017 about virtual reality and augmented reality. We got to experience virtual reality using the OnePlus Loop VR Headsets. And tomorrow I am participating in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.terryfoxrunchennai.in/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Terry Fox Run&lt;/a&gt;. So, wish me luck!&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 23:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/weakened-in-weekends/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/weakened-in-weekends/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ambivalence</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;In recent times, maybe weeks or months, a kind of vacillation has gripped my mind. Its intensity keeps growing with time, and peaks at the minute of call. This indecision is like Betaal which doesn't want to let go of me. From trying to decide which route to take back home, to planning my day, I seem to be going bonkers about what to do. Even as I am typing this line, I'm thinking about whether I should complete this piece, study physics, or just listen to Kenny Sebastien and laugh.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This dichotomy is not just limited to indecision. I am an ambivert. I will put all my efforts to avoid speaking to someone on the phone, often even a close aide or a yesteryear friend. The Internet deserves a part of the blame. Even when I need to get some work done or some information, I avoid talking to people, even those I've known for years, for a simple reason, &quot;I'll just Google it.&quot; Now-a-days, unsurprisingly, stopping en route and asking for directions has become obsolete; thanks to all the satellites, networks, and smart-phones. Nevertheless, often the extrovert in me wakes up. I begin to speak to complete strangers with ease. I go on a introductory spree and get to know new people and associate them with places and things. In the new college that I have come to, I have spoken to a minimum of a hundred people, but remember less than fifty of their names.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Either because of all the ragging that took place in colleges, or due to their exaggerated portrayal in movies like 3 Idiots, a policy has been taken up in IITM: All freshie hostels should be free of higher year students. Now, this puts me in a dilemma. Am I to meet my seniors or not? I have heard about freshies being invited to seniors' rooms in the night for interaction, but never been there. I have friends who have done that and they have exceedingly different experiences to share. Some say they were made to do things, act, sing, and dance, while others say they were offered genuine advice and support. One was even offered unused almost-sparklingly new books. I currently have a small experiment going on in my head to understand the difference between what happens of people who know many seniors, and people like me who know few. I even have some subjects and data points ready!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To pursue a job or not to was a decision I would have found daunting. But the road just got a lot steeper. Now, I have to choose and decide many things. NCC, NSS, or NSO (National Sports Organisation)? If NSO, which sport? What else do I go for? We have a club for everything: from Music, Dance, Thespian, to Comedy, Writing, Oratory, to Quiz, and Word Games, and many more. And for someone who doesn't fit any particular category, there is the Informals Club. And between all this, I have to study too! Just Kidding! I know why I am here, and if you would have read my previous post, you would too. Let's hope I get to use some of the tricks up my sleeves, and make good decisions.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 16:15:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/ambivalence/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/ambivalence/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Did I End Up Here?</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is a very unusually high probability that you, or any people you encounter, believe in one of these two theories: The Theory of Destiny or The Theory of Random Events. Followers of the former believe that every action, event, or decision taken, human or otherwise, has been written down. There is neither a way to change it, nor escape it. On the other hand, people like me believe that nothing in the universe occurs as a planned series of events. Things happen and you flow with it; believing that you had a role to play in it. You do what you can. And improvise.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All through high school, I knew I was interested in science. I wanted to delve into it. I had to study the foundations and build upon it. &quot;But, science is so vast. Where do I begin?,&quot; I thought. Great advices come from people you don't actually believe in. That happened with me, during class 10. Some college principal advised me to study all the basic sciences, including biology. And I did. I studied Physics, Chemistry, Math, and Biology, in Class 11 and 12. Little did I know he was right.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the winter of '14, I attended an INSPIRE Internship Camp. It was organised by GS Science College, Belgaum, and funded by Dept. of Science and Technology, Govt. of India. The intention of the camp was to inspire youth to make careers in science. For me, it was just a reassurance that I was going along the right path.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The camp revolved around all of the basic sciences, but I was attracted to Biology. Dr. Bhaskar Joshi's lecture on Stem Cells and Regenerative Medicine inspired me. Dialogue with him on differentiation of artificial stem cells showed me what I want to do in the future. That's when I said, &quot;Biology, it is.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-S3pYN9MEdcs/V7AWKgsZkhI/AAAAAAAAAI8/vnrx_CHAlBUHxbJvLYRMkNtPJJWQqHarACK4B/s1600/20.JPG&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;197&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-S3pYN9MEdcs/V7AWKgsZkhI/AAAAAAAAAI8/vnrx_CHAlBUHxbJvLYRMkNtPJJWQqHarACK4B/s400/20.JPG&quot; title=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;TOP RIGHT - Dr. Bhaskar Joshi, with mic. in hand.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;i&gt;For the whole INSPIRE photo album, http://sites.canvera.com/photobook.php?pin=6383813416&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The milestones was fixed. All I needed to do was find a good-enough college ready to take me in. There were some where I wanted to go, but they couldn't take me in, like Harvard or IISc, Bengaluru. Then there were others who were ready to take me in, but I didn't want to go, like IISER - Pune and IISER - Kolkata. An equilibrium was reached at IIT Madras. So, here I am, studying Biological Sciences, in a BS-MS Dual Degree Research Program.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/6/69/IIT_Madras_Logo.svg/1024px-IIT_Madras_Logo.svg.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/6/69/IIT_Madras_Logo.svg/1024px-IIT_Madras_Logo.svg.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;shrinkToFit transparent&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/6/69/IIT_Madras_Logo.svg/1024px-IIT_Madras_Logo.svg.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;These are some of the random events that have brought me here. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 12:51:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/how-did-i-end-up-here_14/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/how-did-i-end-up-here_14/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CORNERS</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&quot;Cozy, isn't it?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;I knew you'd ask,&lt;br /&gt;If not for the curtains,&lt;br /&gt;I'd be sure to bask.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Comfortable, it is,&lt;br /&gt;I am the Grouch,&lt;br /&gt;But, take me there,&lt;br /&gt;I'd love to crouch.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Push me there,&lt;br /&gt;I'll put you out,&lt;br /&gt;I have my supports,&lt;br /&gt;Don't need another bout.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I'm solid, I'm colourful,&lt;br /&gt;But, expect no pamper;&lt;br /&gt;&quot;It surely is cozy&quot;&lt;br /&gt;I'd love to answer. &lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 14:38:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/corners/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/corners/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Back in Black</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Hi People..!!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;I am back,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Back in Black.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Its been a really long time since I've updated the blog. Actually, its been a really long time since I've written anything at all, (except all the answers in examinations). For the past six months, all I've done is study, and find myself a university which is ready to take me in. Now I find myself in Indian Institute of Technology Madras, studying my favourite subject, Biology.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;And to top it all, I just met the IIT Writing Club yesterday at the Club Weekender. Getting there and talking to the guys prompted me write a poem (that will appear as the next post), and hopefully this is the start of something good. I guess, the club will keep me going and make me write more often.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;More updates about life at IIT Madras will follow (soon).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Without Wax,&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Aditya Jeevannavar&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 14:31:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/back-in-black/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/back-in-black/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hooke's Law Applied to Life</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;I had an idea to write about Hooke's Law and its strikingly accurate representation of human emotions in terms of stress and strain about a month ago, but had to defer the article until today due to exams and college applications. Nevertheless, here it goes.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Hooke's Law states that, under certain physical conditions, the strain produced in a material is directly proportional to the stress applied on it. For simplification, consider a spring; the enlargement in its length is directly proportional to the force applied across its ends. This is an idealized behavior. But what is more interesting is the curve of stress against strain that follows it.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The stress v/s strain curve for most materials is typical. In the initial linear phase, the strain is proportional to stress. But as stress increases beyond the elastic limit, the strain increases rapidly. Eventually, the material reaches a point of ultimate strength where the strain increases irrespective of whether the stress is increased or decreased. And, finally the material reaches its fracture point.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-_90BZrOZ_BQ/Von-QqxMSJI/AAAAAAAAAIQ/y6ZLNHrMWTs/s1600/Stress%2Bvs%2BStrain%2BCurve.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-_90BZrOZ_BQ/Von-QqxMSJI/AAAAAAAAAIQ/y6ZLNHrMWTs/s1600/Stress%2Bvs%2BStrain%2BCurve.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Stress v/s Strain Curve&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;Now, forget all the physics aspect of it. The curve not only represents the behavior of a material under stress, but also represents the emotional strain on a person under stress brilliantly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Most of the boys that I have encountered belong to the initial linear part of the curve. When under stress, they show signs of a proportional amount of strain. Some of the people belonging to this category are too elastic, like steel (appropriately known to have Nerves of Steel); it takes a lot of stress to produce an infinitesimal strain. Take, for example, bureaucrats, judges (not the TV reality show ones), angel investors, etc. I consider myself also to be a representative of this category (thanks to my genes). Whenever I feel I am under stress, I just take a good look at myself in the mirror, and go silent and solitary unto the next morning. But, the thought of becoming excited, happy or sad when many expect me to be just doesn't get to my mind. I can't see why most people can't be like this, if not for the fear of the world becoming dull because of all the monotonous people.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Most of the girls that I encounter belong to the non-linear part of the curve. Even a little spark causes a wildfire. Even something as small as an original book about 'One Direction' gets them excited and jumping with joy. These are the people who find joy in the little things. But the reason I don't like it is that there is always a disaster waiting to strike. Even a mildly disappointing news like a par score in a test can push a person into depression.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But, for all the people, the complete curve is actually applicable. After a threshold point, even the most stoic person will experience a significant amount of strain for a small stress, and then beyond the point of ultimate strength, even if the stress decreases, the strain accumulates. And finally, the person meets his fracture point, where either his body or his mind gives away. I guess we can compare this to a heart patient's condition, you give very bad news or very good news, the only place they will reach is the fracture point.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;I do understand that no generalizations are accurate (including this one), but I found these observations right enough to be written about. What do you think? Which category do you belong to, the stoic or the boisterous?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 20:14:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/hookes-law-applied-to-life/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/hookes-law-applied-to-life/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are Hindus Born or Made?</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;According to Hindu Law, Hindus are born, while some are made, by conversion. According to Wikipedia, Religion is a set of organised beliefs. So, a Hindu is a person who believes in Hindu principles. I fail to comprehend how a Hindu can be born. This would imply that a child, as soon as it is born, has full knowledge of all such beliefs and customs, and agrees to become a Hindu. I feel, every person is born amorphous, and then made into a follower. In India, where just about everyone is interested in knowing your religious affiliation, one must be careful of the consequences one will have to face after answering it. Born into a Hindu family, I am now 17 years old, and still don't know about the intricacies of Hinduism. If just being born into a Hindu family makes me Hindu, and there is no difference whether I concur with its beliefs or no, then I find this to be futile concept.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To understand it better, let's go back to the origin of Hinduism. During ancient history, Aryans used the term Hindus for people living East of the river Sindhu (now Indus). Then, under the Aryan rule, Hinduism referred to the Aryan Caste System (Varna Vyavastha) of Kshatriyas, Bramhins, Vaishyas, and Shudras. Then, comes the modern interpretations of Hinduism as a religion. So, Hinduism actually originated as sects of people divided based on the way they lived or the work they performed. If we extrapolate the same theory for a time 2000 years in the future, we will see teachers forming a separate religion, and likewise engineers, scientists, doctors, politicians, all forming separate religions. That will be a time when a doctor's child will be declared a doctor by birth, just as a Hindu's child is pronounced Hindu by birth. One easily accepts the latter, but not the former; Why? Can a small child know whether his body, mind, and conscience, will allow him to be a doctor, or a teacher, or just about anything at the time of birth? Doesn't the same analogy apply to religion?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Is the concept of religion valid in this modern generation of science and technology? We hear from all quarters about how one has to accept failure, face adversaries, and strive to progress. If religion supports coping with such pressures and getting accepted in the society, then it can be accepted with open arms, but in a society where religion has become the root cause of multiple problems, I believe it has to be shunned. Proper value education and an active conscience obviate the need for a religion to govern society. When virtues are the need of the hour, religion is not doing much help.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If we view it from a very broad perspective, a religious group is not very different from a social club, if not more evolved (not superior), pompous, and having a large following. You get to meet new people and have a good conversation starter, since both perform the same old rituals. But, this never guaranties meeting like-minded people. One gets to meet like-minded people in clubs of one's interest, be it a sports club, social club, recreational club, or professionals' club. Other than networking, religious groups readily offer people who can support you, in a fight. This is one of religious people's worst habits. Just because a person belongs to your religion, you mustn't blindly support him, unaware of any possible criminal motives that he may have. By any means, one can garner better support by being a good human being, and not by merely being part of an out-spoken sect.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I think, this division of people based on religions is an ingenious scientist's off-the-records genetic experiment. What better way could there be to segregate people living in the same neighborhood? One can easily study populations living in the same physical conditions, but reproductively isolated. If you think about it, it is one of the best way to observe human genes and their inheritance in action.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Forcibly performing rituals, talking to religiously equal people and ignoring others, and finding religions and non-existent castes and sub-castes to fill out application forms, will either induce inferiority complex or megalomania. Just as every person is given the opportunity to choose his occupation, hobbies, and lifestyle, I believe, every person, on reaching adulthood, should be given the opportunity to choose the religion he wishes to be affiliated to, or to none at all.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 17:17:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/are-hindus-born-or-made/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/are-hindus-born-or-made/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GOD = CONSCIENCE</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;I don't believe in the concept of God, as the creator and controller of the universe, or as a supreme being having authority and power over nature and man. I aspire to become a scientist, someone who explores, observes, and interprets. I hope to be an oar to take humanity's boat across the treacherous waters of ignorance, to the island of knowledge; and the belief, in God as a supreme being, is the biggest hurdle in our way. This entity is like a small island in the sea. It can accommodate all, not without conflict, but it makes man a vegetable. In the comfort of this island, we lose the instinct to explore. I'd rather hop on a raft and explore the open seas, than stay complacent on a soon-to-capsize island.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;People preach about God citing lines from scriptures and holy books. Well, these scriptures and holy books are nothing more than stories and theories. Ancient scholars wrote about their experiences and interpretations as stories, and presented them as theories to explain the behaviour of an ideal man, just as Darwin proposed a theory for evolution and Mendel proposed a theory to explain inheritance (of course, with much less recorded observations). Just because theories appealed to our ancestors, doesn't mean they are universal truths. They are to be questioned, and when proved wrong, people must adopt a newer theory to allow for newer observations.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In any case, scriptures are just compilations of stories. They were written to be interpreted as metaphors, not verbatim. They were written to guide people, not to scare them into doing certain things. We must make ourselves capable of reading between the lines, interpreting the stories, deriving the morals, and applying them in our lives. Scriptures are great storehouses of our ancestors' knowledge and lives; Reading them gives us a measure of the change and development, and the depth of history. But, the obstacle hindering our efforts of tapping into this knowledge is language. Many of the ancient languages like Sanskrit and Hebrew are no longer in common use. So, for the attainment of that knowledge, one has to learn a wholly different language. Since most of us can't, we have to turn to translations. Translators, no matter how good, are bound to err, get stumped at some point, and add in their own interpretations. This leads much loss of actual matter, and ambiguity. I've heard that scriptures have so many stories that a clever man, citing different connotations, can prove two contradictory statements true. Thus, all-believing non-investigative naive common people become prey to faithless vulpine group of greedy individuals.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A proverb I find worth debating over and proving false is, 'The fear of God is the beginning of Wisdom'. I mean, really, what wisdom is the adage hinting at. Fear always leads to ignorance, never to wisdom. I have&amp;nbsp;often&amp;nbsp;come across this fear. People tell, don't do this, else God will punish you, or do this to make God happy and he will grant your wishes. I believe Man punishes Himself, Conscience punishes Man; but never God. Weak people need God. For example, consider you are waiting for a bus, and a man standing close to you starts smoking. The strong one will oppose him, force him to stop causing harm to others, while the weak will just have thoughts running in his mind like,&quot;What can I do?&quot;, &quot;I'm mot strong enough&quot;, &quot;It is out of my reach&quot;, and &quot;God will punish him.&quot; I don't fear God, but I do fear faith and tradition. Every day, one or&amp;nbsp;the other quack&amp;nbsp;pops up with mindless acts and prophecies, that he says have been performed for years as tradition. Faith in such mindless and diverse tradition is sure to lead to conflict and loss to everyone involved.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Recently, in the newspaper, I read an article about spirituality in the act of yajna. Yajna is not performed for the satisfaction of some supreme outward entity, but for the purification of the mind and conscience. To perform a yajna, one must abstain from smoking, consuming alcohol, narcotic drugs, cooked food, and celibate, for a period of time. Thus, yajna purifies one's body, and a sound body hosts a sound mind. This mind is the god that the yajna, or any ritual for that matter, is supposed to act upon, not some supreme entity residing in the skies. I believe the supreme entity that few worship and many fear must reside in the mind. I believe the supreme entity is CONSCIENCE.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 22:42:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/god-conscience/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/god-conscience/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Teacher's Day</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Every year, in memory of Dr. Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan, the 5th day of September is celebrated as Teacher's day. This day usually turns out to be either very bland, or celebrated in a meaningless and pompous way, with gifts and cakes. I regret it when such a day, meant for inspiration and appreciation, is wasted on futile entertainment. As a small step in a new direction, I, on behalf of my classmates, wrote a letter to my teachers, to inspire them and make them inspire us. And we delivered the letter to them one day prior to Teachers' Day. The letter read as follows:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dear Teacher,&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;You're an ocean of knowledge, we're empty barrels waiting to be filled. But, we do not seek filtered and purified water, devoid of all its qualities. We want the water with all the salts and impurities in it, whether by means of a pipe, a pail, or handfuls.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You have so much of knowledge, potential, stories, and energy to share, but why do you get entangled in the net of marks. We do not care about how many questions are asked in the exam or what they are. We do not want to know whether mugging up a concept is going to yield us 5 marks in the exam. We do not want to measure a concept merely by the marks it is worth in an exam. We want to understand the various facets of science and society alike; we want them to inspire us. More importantly, we want you to help us understand, and get inspired.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Coming to more real-world scenario, many of our seniors got and surely, many of us will get sky high percentage of marks in the board exams; its just been made so easy and &amp;nbsp;predictable. According to many, the real hurdles are competitive exams. These hurdles appear unbreachable because we don't understand the core concepts, because all we are ever taught in class is, &quot;How to get good marks?&quot;, instead of the &quot;Core Learning&quot;, and &quot;Concepts of Science&quot;. Learning without purpose is not only useless, it is harmful. Its like knowing the rules and procedure, without knowledge of the vocabulary and aim. This is a precise definition of cancer - growing without purpose. But, we believe, this malignant cancer can be cured with small doses of inspiration and enlightenment.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We believe, you, as a teacher, have the greatest of powers and the heaviest of duties - you shape generations. This teachers' day, we want you to shine your lantern upon us, guide us, and share with us the most valuable lessons of your life. We want 'you' to teach us, inspire us, enlighten us.....&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With Regards,&lt;br /&gt;Your obedient students,&lt;br /&gt;Section G - Class of 2016&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Through this letter, I euphemistically told them that I am fed up of the marks-oriented teaching and desperately in need of change. The first signs of my letter's effects were seen when our chemistry teacher told us his story. He told us how, in the initial stages of his career, he too wanted to teach us in an idealistic manner, focusing on the concept rather than the marks. But, in the few years he has been teaching, he felt the pressures of completing the prescribed syllabus in the the limited time made available. Nevertheless, he has promised that he will make sure that our learning is more interactive and inspirational.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But, unfortunately, the euphony misled some of our teachers to believe that the letter was a thank you card. After 2-3 such reactions, where they were just happy that we appreciated their efforts and that we thanked them, I began to feel that either I had beaten too much around the bush or they had failed to take the criticism. Their reactions governed them rather than responses. The results of the exercise deviated sharply from the expected one, but I sure learned two things, that I should keep reasonable expectations from others and that most people react and seldom respond.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 22:16:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/teachers-day/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/teachers-day/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scores!! Scores?? Scores?!</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Scores will score good scores,&lt;br /&gt;What can we infer from them?&lt;br /&gt;Will we be knowledgeable citizens?&lt;br /&gt;Or just laymen with huge recollections?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Do scores have a role, even when the questions are easily predicted?&lt;br /&gt;Or is it just a formality, that needs to be completed?&lt;br /&gt;Do scores reflect test-taker's expertise, or the test's level of ease?&lt;br /&gt;Or do they show one's capacity to mug up, or one's ability to duplicate?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A dolt who can't tell a lion from a buck,&lt;br /&gt;Gets great scores by sheer luck;&lt;br /&gt;Who's the culprit of the dolt's duncehood;&lt;br /&gt;The tester, the testee or the proctor?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Concepts are the core we fail to comprehend,&lt;br /&gt;And use the scores to defend,&lt;br /&gt;Parents and peers we may offend,&lt;br /&gt;But, eventually, against what else to fend?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The clever judge their own scores, assimilate the data,&lt;br /&gt;The less endowed compare;&lt;br /&gt;Anxiety, depression, fury - the emotions run wild,&lt;br /&gt;The dust settles in the desert of lost hope.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Scores are stars, but can we land on them?&lt;br /&gt;We need a check, seldom, but we need not depend.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 22:41:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/scores-scores-scores/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/scores-scores-scores/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ingratitude</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Why be thankful, when you can be of use?&lt;br /&gt;You gain nothing, neither do you lose.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We hear of Nature's fruits getting rotten,&lt;br /&gt;And shrill cries of,&quot;What have we begotten?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;Nature's filled with matter,&lt;br /&gt;And matters we're overwhelmed with;&lt;br /&gt;We're all against the slaughter,&lt;br /&gt;But ignorant of the pith.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why offer thanks, and wash off our hands?&lt;br /&gt;Let's stand upright, and run the errands.&lt;br /&gt;Harming nature is hard, halting much harder,&lt;br /&gt;Everything we do is a system of barter.&lt;br /&gt;Some of us destroy, few others try repair,&lt;br /&gt;But, all of us do it to repel despair.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Does the bee buzz around, thanking the flowers?&lt;br /&gt;Or do cows offer blades of grass to the God?&lt;br /&gt;Does a seedling stop growing, pausing for others?&lt;br /&gt;Then why are we so adamant about our abode?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The lion doesn't thank the grasses for camouflage;&lt;br /&gt;The bear doesn't thank the water for its catch;&lt;br /&gt;The sparrow doesn't thank the soil for the worms;&lt;br /&gt;Then have we lost our instinct?&lt;br /&gt;Or do we prefer hypocrisy?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nature has made us evolve, it permit us to think and implement;&lt;br /&gt;If remain naive and obsequious, we'll have to repent.&lt;br /&gt;Respect it, utilize it, ameliorate it and sustain its presence,&lt;br /&gt;For there's no room for gaucherie, neither for irreverence.&lt;br /&gt;But, why be thankful, when you can be of use?&lt;br /&gt;You gain nothing, neither do you lose.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 21:58:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/ingratitude/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/ingratitude/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Knowledge or Grades? What's more important?</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;I don’t like to complain, but the current teaching scenario doesn’t earn any appreciation either. I hate it when my teachers break into the same old monotonous speech on marks, marks and marks. How can something as valuable as knowledge be measured in marks or grades? Is it even possible to catalogue a man based on the marks or grades he earns?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ever so often, my teachers tend to assign an arbitrary number of marks to each and every concept. They've developed a habit of it. Most of them, at most times, tell, &quot;This concept is important for 2 marks&quot;; &quot;That definition is a definite question for 1 mark&quot;; &quot;One numerical is guaranteed from this concept&quot;; &quot;This derivation will be asked for 5 marks.&quot; I don't understand why teachers are so compelled to categorize topics based on marks assigned to them in the examinations. But, the worst bit is when they skip fundamental concepts citing the reason that no questions pertaining to such concepts are asked in examinations. They say that certain concepts are 'not important from the exam point of view' and that not studying such concepts wouldn't amount to any loss. Some ignorant students follow such teachers blindly and study only for the sake of exams. These lethargic students find the easiest ways to score the most marks with the least efforts, discovering shortcuts, finding frequently asked questions, and skipping unimportant topics. Many students are inclined to mug up the answers to the most anticipated questions in the examinations. They get ready to face the exams, but not to apply their knowledge.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;According to me, the cause for such marks-driven pedagogy is a fundamental flaw in people's ideology- people tend to judge individuals, their character, their capabilities, and everything in between, on the basis of marks. If 'A' gets 95 marks out of 100 in any arbitrary subject, then people begin to praise A to the sky; &quot;Oh! A's so intelligent! A's so smart!'; people never take A's character, aim, interests or personality into consideration. Similarly, if 'B' gets 40 marks on the same test, then the same people begin to treat B irreverently. Most fail to consider B's circumstances; whether B was unwell or uninterested or just had other priorities and commitments. It is true that if an individual can't score good marks, then he is a bit weak in prioritizing and decision-making, but that shouldn't mar his image for a lifetime. We mustn't judge anyone by virtue of his marks. Take the example of Albert Einstein, or Thomas Edison, or even Mark Zuckerberg. Both Einstein and Edison were considered dim and foolish by pedagogues, because they rebelled against rote learning. Now, tell me, can we imagine Einstein and Edison fools, just because they didn't do well in school; or Zuckerberg as bogus because he dropped out of college?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Knowledgeable students will garner good marks, but good marks do not imply knowledge. One shouldn't sow rotten seeds in small pots, add kilos of fertilizers and expect beautiful flowers. The time has come for education to stop centering on marks and start centering on character-building. Education should be an inspiration, not a burden. Knowledge and character must be supreme, not marks.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 11:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/knowledge-or-grades-whats-more-important/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/knowledge-or-grades-whats-more-important/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Contentment</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Self contentment brings happiness,&lt;br /&gt;But does the happiness need self?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For if I loved books, I'd be a librarian;&lt;br /&gt;If I loved food, I'd be a cook;&lt;br /&gt;If I loved money, I'd be a banker;&lt;br /&gt;But does this contentment have an end?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I am content,&lt;br /&gt;When my house is my home,&lt;br /&gt;When there is conversation in silence,&lt;br /&gt;When my thoughts aren't solitary,&lt;br /&gt;Even when I'm asleep.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But one mustn't stop with complacency;&lt;br /&gt;For I'd rather be incomplete,&lt;br /&gt;Than stay in the dark,&lt;br /&gt;And assume I'm complete.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 06:42:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/contentment/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/contentment/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Procrastination</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;The bitter reality of every hard working, yet low achieving person is procrastination. It is a tendency that is very hard to avoid. Take this article for example. I put the heading up last week and planned to write it. Time and again, I postponed, pushing the day further for one reason or the other. I guess, the time is right only now, for I will not procrastinate any longer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For the past few weeks, I've been thinking of discussing, with the principal, about a few reforms in the functioning of our college, but could never find the right thread to pull. Firstly, our college neither has a student counselor, nor does it have a suggestion box. Whom do I speak to? This is one of the matters I wanted to discuss about. Autumn is creeping in faster than I imagined. In two months, I'll have to start writing my college applications, and with no counselor, completing it won't be easy. I have yet to find out who in our college has the authority and the ability to complete the official parts of my college application as a school representative.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Secondly, our college library's modus operandi is one the most peculiar and worst kind I have ever seen. All the books are kept behind glass walls and to read any of them, one has to affix one's identity card. So, obviously, the librarians have trust issues. But, that isn't the end of it. One is allowed to borrow only one book among limited options, that too only on a specified date once in two weeks. I feel as if the librarian decides what I read and when I read it. The other day, one of the librarians told me that many old books had been stacked, bundled and kept in a storeroom on the top floor of the library building, inaccessible to potential readers. They could have been leased to students or, even donated to economically or academically poor students. But, no; they had to take the stupid decision and pack the books off for rodents to bite at. I don't know what one needs to know to become a librarian, but I'm sure librarians in our college library are unqualified for the post. In nearly all libraries, the situation is so pathetic that I've never seen a librarian as a book lover. Librarians at the counter often sit playing games on the computer, never caring to read a book from among the thousands around them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thirdly, the cultural and co-curricular activities in our college are nearly equal to nil, qualitatively and quantitatively. Our principal doesn't even permit us to participate in fests organised by other colleges; Fests in our college are out of the question. When some of my friends and I had opted for a French language course, the principal dashed our aspirations and asked us to concentrate on the core science subjects. The very soul of our college has become resistive&amp;nbsp;to cultural expression and extra-curricular activities. The only active group in our college is the eco-club comprising of lecturers only. I don't know why; I'm going to find that out soon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now, surely, I will no longer wait for someone to take the lead, neither till someone asks me for my opinion. I will take the lead. I will ask the questions and I will get the answers I need. I will open the forum for discussion. I will try and I will succeed.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 22:26:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/procrastination/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/procrastination/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LIVE AND LET LIVE</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Should we interrupt in Nature's Deeds?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In our last biology class, our teacher was telling us about human activities' &quot;ill-effects&quot; on ecosystems and that protecting the ecosystems is our responsibility. Many people believe that construction of wildlife sanctuaries and bio-reserves, adoption and care of animals, and collection, storage and preservation of plant specimens (seeds) are methods to do so. But, I strongly oppose most of it. We shouldn't interrupt in nature's deeds, either&amp;nbsp;for the bad or what we assume is good!!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We have a long-standing habit of poking our nose into everything and doing things without giving much regards to &amp;nbsp;its consequences. Firstly, we managed to change (others prefer destroy) our environment with our habitation, agriculture, and industrialization. Frankly speaking, I don't find any flaw in it. We are as much a part of the environment as it is of us. As inhabitants of the Earth, we have every right to make our stay here comfortable; but we also have the duty to accept the ramifications of ours' as well as our cohabitants', animals, plants and microbes, activities. Secondly, claiming ourselves to be the smartest species in the generations to come, we indulge in activities to protect nature. Why do we want to conserve nature in its current state? Are we afraid of the future? Afraid that species smarter than us may evolve, and dominate us? Treat us as we now treat chimps?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We are either incorrigible hypocrites or ingenuous ignorants. One should either be selfless or accept that we are selfish. Why be a hypocrite? We speak so much of conservation of nature; protecting nature for nature's sake, for animals' and plants' sake. Did they ask us for protection? Aren't we obligated to all such things? But, I believe we actually do all of it for our own sake. We have feasts during holy festivals, don't we? Why? Because, we want to, but we take the name of God as if he demanded us to have such a sumptuous meal. Why do we treat others respectfully and courteously? Because, we often expect the same attitude in return. If it was ensured that no matter how you behaved, others would treat you respectfully, I bet, most people's true character would come out.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;If we are not hypocrites, then we are ignorants for failing to consider the aftermath of our actions. We often hear that the number of species on Earth are decreasing, and that species loss is our loss. I believe it is just nature's way of filtering out the incompatible. When we change, the nature around us changes. If some species are dying, some more better suited species are being generated. Saving a mere two or three species will not sustain the future. Nature has its own ways of solving problems and speciation is one of the best it has come up with. Origin of man was a result of speciation. If we stop obstructing nature at every path, it will redeem itself; it will speciate. Nature will balance itself; not restore, but balance!!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Studying substantial parts of history, evolution and pre-historic life, the one thing that we can deduce is that change is inevitable. Yet, we resist it. Whenever something new happens, whether gradually or suddenly, we become hysterical. We hear that only a thousand tigers are left in India, and we begin worrying- What to do? What to do?? Let's try this! Let's try that!! I say, stop all this bullshit and reassess the scenario. For a change, let's not do anything, and wait for nature to complete its move. Remember, humans evolved from nature ans not the other way round. Let's stop interfering and allow nature to get its act back together. Let's live and let live!!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 22:44:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/live-and-let-live/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/live-and-let-live/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can Man Be Unselfish? Of Course Not!!</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Selfishness is a character that compels one to keep the whole or at least a part of anything and everything for oneself. Although used in a very derogatory sense, selfishness is an inherent trait in every organism, be it - unicellular or multi-cellular, mobile or immobile, domesticated or wild. It is the driving force behind the development of man and one of the most influential motivations.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Charles Darwin was right when he spoke of, 'The survival of the Fittest,' (Although he referred fitness, ultimately and only, to reproductive fitness, I believe fitness refers to the combination of all the favourable traits.) Selfishness is in our genes, and its one of the fundamental characters passed on to us by our ancestors. Only selfish people incited by a tinge of selflessness went a long way and they still do!! Plain selflessness neither inspires one, nor does it motivate one to beat the odds and do something new. Selfishness renders one fit and the fittest always survive.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;'Man loves himself most.' I've read at least two stories having this as their moral and I wish to cite the two. In one story by Mannu Bhandari, a cemetery comes upon a widower who is extremely sad and is weeping over the death of his wife. The cemetery expects the man to die in despair, but in the span of a couple of years, it again comes upon the same individual mourning the death of his second wife. The cemetery condones the man, thinking of his acts as an aberration, but when it again finds the man lamenting, this time due to the death of his third wife, it realizes that man loves oneself most and that he is always ready to scale immense heights to find peace and happiness for oneself.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In another Akbar and Birbal story, Birbal arranges for an experiment to prove that one loves one's own life most. He puts a monkey and its baby in a deep tank and asks the servants to start pouring water into it. As the water level rose to the mother's knee, it picks up the baby and places it against its bosom. When the water reaches its hips, it places the baby on its shoulder. When the water level reaches its shoulders, it places the baby on top of its head. But, when the water level seems to rise above its nose, it puts the baby down and stands on top of it to save its own life. Thus, the experiment showed that one loves one's own life most.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Although I speak so much for selfishness, I don't intend to support it under its current definition. I believe that we shouldn't let selfishness limit only up to I; it should cover the expanse of I, my family, my people, my nation, my Earth and even my galaxy (not ruling out inter-galactic communication in the near future.) I believe selfishness under the right control can be a very positive inspiration and motivation.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 22:21:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/can-man-be-unselfish-of-course-not/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/can-man-be-unselfish-of-course-not/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Novel Predilection</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Over the past few years, I've developed an affinity for novels in the mystery, suspense, thriller and conspiracy genre. I've gone onto read novels written by Dan Brown, Robert Ludlum, Sir Arthur Conan Doyle and Stieg Larsson.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The penchant for mystery novels began when I was in class 5. I had borrowed the first edition of Famous Five, by Enid Blyton, from the new library in the township. The Famous Five kept me so engrossed that I couldn't let go without reading the entire series. I was effectively hooked on, reading an edition every week. I managed to read 18 out of the 21 book series in the year, since 2 of them were damaged and 1 missing from the library. All-in-all, the Famous Five brought me to the mystery adventure genre.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Over the next two years, I experimented reading books from authors like O. Henry and Chetan Bhagat, but nothing could satiate that lust for mystery and adventure. Later, my sis bought an edition of Dan Brown's The da Vinci Code, but couldn't finish it. When I managed to get my hands on it, I couldn't put it down. I was mesmerized by the conspiracy, the mystery and the thrill it enveloped. The in -a-day narration and attention to detail had me head-over-heels in love with the style of writing. Consequently, I devoured - Angels &amp;amp; Demons, Deception Point, Digital Fortress, The Lost Symbol, and Inferno - all by Dan Brown. I am desperately waiting for his next novel. His conspiracy stories have left me wanting for more.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On &amp;nbsp;the look for more, I found Stieg Larsson's Millennium Trilogy. He originally wrote in Swedish, but the English translations - The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo, The Girl Who Played With Fire, and The Girl Who Kicked The Hornet's Nest - are superb. The characters, Lisbeth Salander and Mikael Blomkvist are built and developed extremely well. Stieg Larsson pulls you into a wormhole and you can't escape until you read the entire trilogy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I'm on the hunt for more mystery and conspiracy. Do tell me if you know of any such good thrillers.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 13:11:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/a-novel-predilection/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/a-novel-predilection/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>EUROTRIP</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;My first chance to use my passport as something other than a photo identity proof proved to be a serene experience across 10 western European countries. We travelled the countries- England, France, Belgium, Netherlands, Germany, Switzerland, Liechtenstein, Austria, Italy and the Vatican City.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The build-up to the trip started two months before the actual trip itself. We had to drive from Belgaum to the city of Bangalore for document verification and bio-metrics for the U.K. Visa. Fortunately, one of my of &amp;nbsp;maternal uncles stays in Bangalore, abating the officialism of the 400 km drive. Obtaining the Shenzhen Visa was easier as we didn't have to go in-person to apply for it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The build-up gained pace two weeks prior to the trip with the anxiety of deciding what to wear and what to take setting in. We bought some winter clothes although we were to visit Europe in spring, as Europe's springs are significantly cooler than our winters. One week prior to our trip, my sister was diagnosed with shopping fever and she had to visit just about every garment store in Belgaum to cure it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We reached Mumbai one day prior our departure for Europe, parked our car at another of my maternal uncle's home and set off in a cab at 10 in the night, thus kick-starting our trip.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;DAY 1&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;0000 IST&lt;br /&gt;We're here, at last! Chhatrapati Shivaji International Airport: Terminal 2! Luckily, the Meru Cab came on time and drrropped us off competently. At first glance, the terminus looks mesmerizing and magical.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;0005 IST&lt;br /&gt;Where is the tour coordinator? Tring Tring... Tring Tring.... Tring Tring.... No answer. I guess, we were too early for our 0640 departure, but the feeling of impatience stayed inexorable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;0100 IST&lt;br /&gt;Still no sign of any Kesari representative!! (By the way, we were travelling with Kesari Tours Private Limited) We just strolled around CSIA terminal 2 admiring its mind-boggling architecture.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;0200 IST&lt;br /&gt;Yet more waiting! And no sleep! Walking around the terminal, I saw 2 couples with Kesari apparel. I deduced that they might be from out tour group. After surreptitiously watching them, I was engulfed by a strange feeling: Had we forgotten to pack something or had they over-packed? (The latter turned out to be true)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;0300 IST&lt;br /&gt;Kesari representatives turn up. We meet our tour leader, Mr. Jayesh Mhatre, for the first time (More about him in later sections). It turns out that we were part of the season's first Eurotrip. But, the arrival of Kesari was as much painful as joyous because they brought so much snacks and other stuff that we had to repack our stuff at the terminus! In the next three hours, we checked in, got through security check and emigration and landed at Duty Free Mumbai Shops. I don't get the concept of &amp;nbsp;Duty Free; The prices they sell at are sky-high anyway, around 10 times the actual price, what more taxes were they going to levy?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;0640 - 1340 IST&lt;br /&gt;My first international flight from Mumbai to Istanbul aboard a BOEING 777-300ER. Our seats were shuffled and I had to sit in an aisle different from mom, dad and sis'. I even had to sacrifice my window seat for an unruly couple. The breakfast on-board was a total enigma. I spent my time playing video games and watching Hangover III and a few episodes of Big Bang Theory.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We tasted some Turkish Delight at Istanbul Airport. It tastes very much like the Indian Halwa, but is richer in taste and nutrition. Then, we were off to London in an Airbus 330.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1440 GMT&lt;br /&gt;We landed in Heathrow, but it took us two hours for immigration and baggage collection. Then, we went straight to Holiday Inn M4J4 for some much needed rest to prepare for the next 14 days. We spent the evening relaxing, and acquainting ourselves with Europe's cool climate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Dg9RWeljU9w/VX2fcRTFYSI/AAAAAAAAAEM/13O6iZjjh5g/s1600/Me%2BIN%2BEurope.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;449&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Dg9RWeljU9w/VX2fcRTFYSI/AAAAAAAAAEM/13O6iZjjh5g/s640/Me%2BIN%2BEurope.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Day 2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Early morning showers threatened to dampen our sight-seeing, but by the time we moved from the City of Westminster to The City, the skies cleared and the Sun shone through. Our first stop was the Tower of London, in The City, on the banks of river Thames (a.k.a. London ki Ganga). The tower has a very vast history, from being a castle to prison to palace and now a museum. We saw the Crown Jewels; the largest diamonds in the world, the Stars of Africa and of course, the Koh-i-Noor. We saw the Ravens of the Tower of London, the Yeomen Warders (popularly known as the Beef eaters), and the Grenadier Guards.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We returned to the City of Westminster for lunch at Bangalore Express via the Trafalgar Square. At this moment it gets hard not to go into the following digression. Trafalgar Square has the sculptures of 4 huge lions at each of its corners. The artist who was summoned to sculpt them was famous for painting animals like dogs, horses etc., but neither had he ever sculpted nor had he seen a lion. Using his cat and dog as models, he gave the lions dog's paws and the look of a cat. Even the lions' mouth is kept open like a dog's.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then we made our way through Parliament Square, viewing the Houses of Parliament and the Big Ben, to the Buckingham Palace and the Victoria Monument. Many of my co-tourists felt that the Buckingham Palace is no match for the grandeur of Indian Palaces. But, I believe it is worth a view because of the power it housed and the lineage it still houses.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the afternoon, we visited Madame Tussaud's Wax Museum, one of the funniest parts of our trip. We posed, sometimes exceedingly stupidly, with actors, athletes, politicians, and many other notable figures. But, the best part of Tussaud's was the 4D MARVEL SHOW. The Avengers and Spiderman jumped right in front of my eyes. I was almost compelled to jump out of my seat and &amp;nbsp;join them fight the bad guys.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-2FkD14FzgdM/VX_sZZ-EjGI/AAAAAAAAAE8/2VEgYaUDXvc/s1600/Collages1.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-2FkD14FzgdM/VX_sZZ-EjGI/AAAAAAAAAE8/2VEgYaUDXvc/s640/Collages1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Glimpses of Madame Tussaud's&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;As the Sun descended, we took a ride on the Coka Cola London Eye, grabbing a spectacular view of the sunset and the London skyline along the Thames.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/--dIzJb9ZHsk/VX_qF7nWnMI/AAAAAAAAAEg/pounPLnpJ30/s1600/collage-2015-06-16.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;372&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/--dIzJb9ZHsk/VX_qF7nWnMI/AAAAAAAAAEg/pounPLnpJ30/s640/collage-2015-06-16.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;DAY 3&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We had to wake up at 4 in the morning to catch our 8 'o' clock Eurostar train to Paris. We boarded Eurostar at St. Pancras Terminus, King's Cross Station. The journey by Eurostar was a great experience. We were travelling at 180 kmph under the English Channel and didn't even feel jerks and jolts. The view of the English and french countrysides from the large windows in the pantry car was bucolic. But, the slums surrounding the Gare du Nord, Paris (Paris' North Station) portrayed a drastically different picture of immigrants in France.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We proceeded for lunch at Jodhpur Palace restaurant and then set out to see the beauty of Paris. We learnt about the history of Paris and the French Revolution, and roamed the streets of Paris. One striking thing is the similarity in structure of the buildings.&amp;nbsp;We saw the Louvre Museum, the Jardin des Tuileries (Tuileries Garden), the Place de la Concorde (Concorde Square), Avenue des Champs-Élysées, the Grand Palais (Palace) and many of the 37 bridges on the Seine. Pont Neuf or the New Bridge happens to be the oldest bridge in Paris at around 400 years of age. Its name, which was given to distinguish it from older bridges that were lined on both sides with houses, has remained.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-TyTguynLD-Q/VX_5h07Z-EI/AAAAAAAAAGQ/fLN1KnAZFfE/s1600/BeFunky%2BCollage%2B%25281%2529.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-TyTguynLD-Q/VX_5h07Z-EI/AAAAAAAAAGQ/fLN1KnAZFfE/s400/BeFunky%2BCollage%2B%25281%2529.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the evening, we went to the top of the Eiffel Tower, observing the beauty of Paris' city planning with the backdrop of an equally beautiful sunset. The panoramic view of the city reveals the stunning pattern in the structure and arrangement of buildings. Many of the city blocks actually appear to be shaped as pizza slices. At around 8 'o' clock, we adored the night view of Paris in a cruise in the Seine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Feel Good Factor:&lt;br /&gt;We were in Paris, considered by many as the center of Europe.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;DAY 4&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We allocated the whole day for Disneyland Paris (a.k.a. Euro-Disney). Well, nearly the whole day, as we took the wrong exit from the expressway and managed to reach Disneyland only at 12 'o' clock. The enchanting land requires at least 2-3 days to see and feel, but unfortunately we only had 6 hours to explore it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I went on the following rides:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;it's a small world&quot;&lt;/i&gt;: The happiest cruise that ever sailed around the world.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Captain EO&lt;/i&gt;: A fantastic 3D film relating the adventures of Captain EO, alias Michael Jackson, featuring a rhythm-packed musical soundtrack and a whole host of dazzling special effects.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Indiana Jones and the Temple of Peril&lt;/i&gt;: Face the wrath of the gods on a mine car looping at high speed through ancient temple ruins.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Pirates of the Caribbean&lt;/i&gt;: An adventurous cruise through a pirate attack on a Spanish fortress.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Big Thunder Mountain&lt;/i&gt;: Hurtling through an abandoned gold mine at breathtaking speed aboard a runaway mine train!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-6v_lN94ZFxY/VX_5hmGcA5I/AAAAAAAAAGU/EaXFNmFWoyg/s1600/BeFunky%2BCollage%2B%25282%2529.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-6v_lN94ZFxY/VX_5hmGcA5I/AAAAAAAAAGU/EaXFNmFWoyg/s400/BeFunky%2BCollage%2B%25282%2529.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We had some tongue tingling, stomach filling hot pizza, pasta and gingerbread at the peppy African jungle themed eatery, &lt;i&gt;Colonel Hathi's Pizza Outpost&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;At the day's end was the Disneyland Parade, which I felt would be more amusing for a 6 year old kid than to me. I do appreciate the beauty, the hard-work and the technology behind it, but it just wasn't for me. For me, Disneyland was characterized by the bursts of adrenaline, riding the thundering, spine-chilling roller-coasters.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Feel Good Factor:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;DISNEYLAND!!!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;DAY 5&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We had breakfast in Paris and drove 3 hours continuously to reach Brussels, Belgium. Did you know that Brussels is a 1 hour drive away from 4 different countries. Also, Brussels is called the Capital of Europe, since the European Union is head-quartered there.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As soon as we entered Brussels, we visited the Atomium. It makes for a great picture with one holding the balls (actually, they're supposed to be electrons according to an old disproved atomic model). Post lunch, we proceeded to the Grand Place Square via the statue of Don Quixote and Sancho Panza. The Grand Place or Grote Markt looks exquisite with all the gold laden buildings and their roofs. We had waited long to see the naked symbol of Brussels, the Manneken Pis, but the sheer magnitude of the statue blew us away. It is the life size statue of a 2 year old baby!! We even bought some belgian dark chocolates, and waffles with extra cream and chocolate on top. (My shirt managed to gather more cream than my mouth: tasty in my mouth, but sticky on my shirt!)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NcXufThvBAY/VX_tqKitcEI/AAAAAAAAAFY/4Nv3uZMtnpA/s1600/Me%2BIN%2BEurope3.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NcXufThvBAY/VX_tqKitcEI/AAAAAAAAAFY/4Nv3uZMtnpA/s640/Me%2BIN%2BEurope3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then, we went on a 4-hour long journey into the Netherlands and had dinner at Invitation Restaurant, Noordwijkerhout. The restaurant had a beautiful and serene lake-view, and the dim lights in the dark night helped get rid of all the boredom and stress from the 7-hour journey.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Feel Good Factor:&lt;br /&gt;Breakfast &amp;nbsp;in France&lt;br /&gt;Lunch in Belgium&lt;br /&gt;Dinner in Netherlands&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;DAY 6&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A soon as I wake up in the morning, I open the huge windows of our room and what should I see? Flowers everywhere: flower fields in every direction, all the way to the horizon; red, yellow, blue, violet, you name the colour you want. The previous night, we had arrived in the darkest of nights. We had high expectations of the tulips, but actually seeing the fields shattered them all.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At around 10 in the morning, we reached Keukenhof (Tulip Garden) at Lisse. There were flowers in full bloom up to the boundaries of my vision, but a sort of gloom had set in. My mood had gone downhill, and whenever I am in a bad mood, all wrong things happen around me (usually because of me). I learnt this the hard way that day. First, in the souvenir shop at Keukenhof, I dropped nearly a dozen chocolates from the rack. Then, when we were at McDonald's for lunch, I dropped and spilled half a bottle of Coke on the floor. Then, at the dinner table, I dropped a bottle cap into my plate. (Fortunately, the bottle didn't follow the cap into my plate.) I guess, many things drop with the mood.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-zvv5DIq1Q5I/VX_sWweQOTI/AAAAAAAAAEs/GDbdVTZ6_24/s1600/EUROPE%2B20153.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-zvv5DIq1Q5I/VX_sWweQOTI/AAAAAAAAAEs/GDbdVTZ6_24/s640/EUROPE%2B20153.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;After lunch at McD's, we went for a canal cruise ride in the City of 100 Canals and 1000 Bridges, Amsterdam. Amsterdam is more famous for 3 things- drugs, dine and bikes. Amsterdam is beautiful, but our time in it wasn't. The atmosphere was great, but my mood wasn't.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then, we sped off to Germany, courtesy, the Autobahn. Did you know that there are no speed limits for cars on certain stretches of the Autobahn? Unfortunately, we were in a bus! We first went to Cologne to see the Cologne Cathedral, the massive Gothic structure. During World War II, the allied fighter pilots used this structure as a landmark and hence, never tried to damage it. But, currently it is under restoration to scrub off the black sooty layer on the whole of its outer surface. Then, we had dinner at Ganesha Restaurant, Cologne and called it a night.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;DAY 7&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We spent most of the day travelling: we had to cross Germany- North to South, from Cologne to Zug, Switzerland. But the journey was beautiful, traversing the mystical Black Forest region (Schwarzwald) of Germany and the Magical hills of Switzerland.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This part of the journey happened to be the official introduction of the tour group and I will follow the same thread. I was part of a group of 27, including 2 families, 6 couples (2 newly weds), 2 loners and 4 trainees, led by a charismatic tour leader. The jolly group was the reason why the journey didn't seem so gloomy and boring. We played together, sang together and laughed together. The whole group seemed like a family, and I would have bonded better had I been more gregarious. We were driven around in 9 countries by Robert, a Pole (as in a Polish citizen) in a Polish bus.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We stopped at a Cuckoo Clock Factory (Hofgut Sternen) at Drubba, Titisee in the Black Forest region. The whole workshop/store doubled up as a huge cuckoo clock. I was awestruck at the sight of the variety of cuckoo clocks on show and the craftsmanship and technique that goes into each one of them. we even had lunch there and in desserts, we had Black Forest pastry. (Devouring yummy Black Forest in Black Forest! What more could I ask for?) Then, it was time to say bye-bye to Germany and hello to Switzerland.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-HT6pkghOTjI/VX_2NSdfsLI/AAAAAAAAAF8/3xZI99zKa4s/s1600/germany%2Bcollage.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-HT6pkghOTjI/VX_2NSdfsLI/AAAAAAAAAF8/3xZI99zKa4s/s400/germany%2Bcollage.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Here, we first visited the Rhine Falls. There was a slight drizzle and hence, we had to wear ponchos. The waterfall looks beautiful from a distance, but when we reached a boulder at the base of the falls by a boat and climbed on top of it, the experience was exhilarating. The combination of the drizzling rain and the water spraying from the falls made for an ineffable experience; and the sound of water, UNFORGETTABLE.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then, we went to Zug, near Lucerne to rest for the night.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Feel Good Factor:&lt;br /&gt;RHINE FALLS; Water Above, Water below, Water All Around...!!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;DAY 8&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We went atop Mt. Titilis and even had ice cream in the middle of all the snow. The bliss of having snow all around you can't be explained in words. Its just sheer adrenaline, dopamine and endorphins.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We made our way back down in the afternoon and went to Lucerne. We saw The Lion Monument representing the back-stabbed fallen soldier, while sipping a cup of hot Indian Masala Tea. Then, while everyone else went on a shopping spree, we explored the streets of Lucerne, trying to understand the history, culture and architecture of Switzerland. We later sat on the banks of Lucerne Lake, enjoying the cool breeze and the setting Sun, and soaking in the Swiss Aura.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-eG98xj5NTbo/VX_2P1GUlgI/AAAAAAAAAGE/N3fxmLYhT1Q/s1600/BeFunky%2BCollage.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-eG98xj5NTbo/VX_2P1GUlgI/AAAAAAAAAGE/N3fxmLYhT1Q/s400/BeFunky%2BCollage.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;We had dinner on a cruise in the Lucerne Lake. Then, while everyone danced on the deck, I was overcome by memories of a dear one. I sat alone at the back of the cruise, feeling emotions I had never felt before. The ripples in the water seemed to reflect the ripples in my heart. For the first time in my life, I was emotional!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Feel Good Factor:&lt;br /&gt;Snow..!!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;DAY 9&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We went to Jungfraujoch (a.k.a. Top of Europe) by cogwheel train. The whole day, we had fun in the snow. We even had a snow fight between Kesari Mandali &amp;nbsp;(our tour leader and his apprentices) and Bhidu Company (Sanskruti, Samruddhi, Sanskar, my sis Anisha and me). We bombarded one another with snow atop the mountain, in the train and even on the streets. Everyone was so busy with the snow fight that no one cared to click any pictures. This is just what I felt from day 1: Forget the photos and cameras, and enjoy the moment.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-WOUB6sq3IsA/VX_sY-NogYI/AAAAAAAAAE0/I3lYGxJFIkM/s1600/Collages3.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-WOUB6sq3IsA/VX_sY-NogYI/AAAAAAAAAE0/I3lYGxJFIkM/s640/Collages3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Feel Good Factor:&lt;br /&gt;Snow-fight..!!!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;DAY 10&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After breakfast in Zug, we left for Liechtenstein, a doubly land-locked country between Switzerland and Austria. It is the sixth smallest country in the world with 36,000 happy citizens. Liechtenstein is the only country with no borders and no army. It is bordered on one side by the river Rhine and the other side by mountains. Liechtenstein and Switzerland are separated by unmanned bridges. So, on one end of the bridge, you have Switzerland and the other end, Liechtenstein.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We visited Vaduz, the capital of Liechtenstein, and toured the city in a small road train. Surprisingly, the commentary in the train was in Hindi. Either India has very good relations with Liechtenstein or the country expects lots of tourists from India. We even had Indian lunch there. Then we headed off to Austria.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We first visited Innsbruck. The name of the city comes from the first Bruck (bridge) on the river Inns. We even saw the Goldenes Dacht (Golden Roof) and Maria Theresien Strasse (street). Queen Maria Theresa was known as the mother-in-law of Europe, since she had 16 children and each of them was married off to a royal family in Europe. We stayed the night in Hotel Olympia, Axams atop a snow peak in the Alps.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-87EG6_PiG-Y/VX_uZrsX6qI/AAAAAAAAAFo/4bbnmBKs45s/s1600/Me%2BIN%2BEurope5.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-87EG6_PiG-Y/VX_uZrsX6qI/AAAAAAAAAFo/4bbnmBKs45s/s640/Me%2BIN%2BEurope5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Feel Good Factor:&lt;br /&gt;Breakfast in Switzerland&lt;br /&gt;Lunch in Liechtenstein&lt;br /&gt;Dinner in Austria&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;DAY 11&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We woke up early for a morning walk in the snow. Eventually, everybody else left and I was left to solitarily jog atop the Alps; something that I actually preferred. After the morning chores, we left for Italy's Veneta Province. We saw some beautiful vistas from Alps' snow peaks to the Italian plains to the Mediterranean Sea.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We had lunch in New Venice and then took a Vaparetto, Water Bus ride to Venezia (Old Venice). The only unfortunate thing was that it was raining. My sister even went on to say, &quot;Venice in Rain, Visited in Pain.&quot; But, I believe the rains were blessings in disguise. How else could we have avoided all the crowd in Venice? I stood alone in the middle of St. Mark's Square (considered by many as the busiest square in the world) and soaked in the beauty of Venice. If not for the rain, would I have been able to solitarily experience Venice's Aura? Of course not. I saw the statue of Victor Emanuel II, the Doge's Palace, the Bridge of Sighs, St. Mark's Basilica, St. Mark's Square and so many other monuments. Everything I saw in Venice is worth mentioning. That's the reason the complete city of Venice is a World Heritage Site. We even went on a Gondola ride in the canals of Venice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then, we proceeded for dinner and stay in Padova.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Feel Good Factor:&lt;br /&gt;Jogging atop the Alps and Getting soaked in Venice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;DAY 12&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We entered the Tuscany Province to visit Maranello, the home of Ferrari. My heart started racing and pounding as I saw the spectacular cars in the Ferrari Museum and the Ferrari Dealership.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then we went to Galileo's home-town, Pisa. We saw the Leaning Tower of Pisa in Piazza del Duomo (Pisa's Cathedral Square) and clicked photos of us holding it up. But, none of my co-tourists had a good enough sense of perspective to click a properly aligned photo of mine. And another striking thing in Pisa was street vendors selling (fake) Gucci and Prada bags for 10-20 Euros. The scenario was similar in almost every city. We saw many hawkers, usually immigrants, selling virtually everything- from ponchos to fake merchandise to cheap souvenirs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-hIjFtw6mFQ0/VX_uZzfzMFI/AAAAAAAAAFk/h0mdfrdM2aE/s1600/Me%2BIN%2BEurope6.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-hIjFtw6mFQ0/VX_uZzfzMFI/AAAAAAAAAFk/h0mdfrdM2aE/s640/Me%2BIN%2BEurope6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Next on our schedule was a visit to Florence's Piazza Michelangelo and David. Michelangelo gave David the body of a well-built male, but the face of his mother. And from the viewpoint right in front of David, I saw the spectacular night skyline of Florence. Having read Dan Brown's Inferno, it was very difficult for me not to go out into Florence exploring the places where Robert Langdon had been. We settled for the night in Art-e-Hotel, Perugia, Umbria Province.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;DAY 13&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A common saying goes such,&quot;All Roads Lead to Rome.&quot; I don't know of the other roads, but our's surely did. We reached Rome, Lazio Province just before noon and visited the Flavian Amphitheatre, commonly known as the Roman Colosseum. Although much of its glory has been lost to calamities, its sheer size is still staggering. We further went on a small tour of the city - viewing Piazza Venezia with the new monument, Vittoria (which happens to be 150 years old), Circus Maximus and the ruins of various forums. We then proceeded for lunch at the Maharajah Restaurant.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Post lunch, we spent time in the Vatican City, the smallest country in the world. We entered via the Vatican Museum. Just about everywhere I turned, there was a piece of art, be it paintings, sculptures, mosaics, carvings, tapestries or frescoes. We then paid a visit to the Sistine Chapel, the most famous hall in the world. The frescoes painted by Michelangelo are magnificent, specially the Last Judgement, and the Creation and other Old Testament stories on the ceiling. There is also a small spot on the ceiling from where the paint has fallen off, but no artist has been brave enough to match Michelangelo and repaint the gap.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We then went to St. Peter's Basilica, the largest church in the world. At every turn, there is a work of art. Every painting in the church has been replaced by mosaic, which look original and are camera-friendly. We saw the works of Bernini and Michelangelo. We then made our way into the St. Peter's Square. Then, in the evening, we went to the Trevi Fountain. Well, Rome wasn't built in a day and it can't be seen in a day either.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/--ynt6vqx7xA/VX_tjaXVOTI/AAAAAAAAAFQ/W87B5seRJKQ/s1600/Me%2BIN%2BEurope4.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/--ynt6vqx7xA/VX_tjaXVOTI/AAAAAAAAAFQ/W87B5seRJKQ/s640/Me%2BIN%2BEurope4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Feel Good Factor:&lt;br /&gt;I was in 2 countries at the same time. One of my feet was in the Vatican City, while the other was in Italy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;DAY 14&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For the first time in a fortnight, we woke up at our own pace and got ready in no hurry. We reached Fiumicino Aeroporto Internazionale Leonardo da Vinci at 1115 hours and boarded our Turkish Airlines flight to Istanbul at 1425 hours. We landed late and had to rush to catch our flight to Mumbai. We reached Mumbai the next morning, stayed at my uncle's home and drove back to Belgaum a day later.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 16:01:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/eurotrip/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/eurotrip/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where is your Nose?</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;The other day, my friends and I caused a small stir in front of our classroom and unwittingly made some ingenuous mistakes; all this while a sly vulpine woman kept her watch on us. I am writing this, not because she scolded us, but because she lashed out at us and tried to warn us without ample knowledge of the act.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nowadays, people poke their noses in as many matters as possible, but never realize that they've left out their brains. People tend to gather information (or rumors) from hither and thither, and come to a conclusion spontaneously; never actually trying to know the true version of the incident from the source. This holds true especially for those people who believe it is their job to correct others.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have seen teachers getting frustrated scolding a student; never to realize that they don't even know half the story. They tend to see an activity, which they believe is wrong, and then there is a barrage of scoldings, comments, and suggestions. They fail to ask the most important question, 'WHY?' Slowly, but surely, a smile or even a teasing laugh comes on the victim's face, and the hell breaks loose. Have you ever realized why the student laughs? I believe there are two reasons: either he has realized his mistakes, is regretting it, and is trying to hide his feelings, or he has realized that the teacher is not interested in knowing the root of the problem and there is no way to stop the castigation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After all the rebuke, what is the result? The teacher gets the reputation of being a martinet and consequently the weak-hearted victims will crack a joke behind his/her back to liven things up. It is never a good idea to warn an adolescent, or any person for that matter, because he will go leaps and bounds to know the punishment you are capable of dishing out.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I believe, the only way to correct/improve someone is to make him explain his mistakes and their causes himself, because it is only his conscience that he is answerable to. I believe only conscience can correct a person.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;P.S.&lt;br /&gt;If you find your views supporting or contradicting mine, please do look into the fascinating subject of psychology.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 15:50:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/where-is-your-nose/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/where-is-your-nose/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Humble Beginnings?</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Georgia, Times New Roman, serif;&quot;&gt;&quot;Guys, who's class is it?&quot;; &quot;Oh, no&quot;; &quot;Let's catch up in the canteen&quot;; these are the hushed voices one hears in our class before a lecturer arrives; and what happens after the lecturer arrives is ineffable.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Georgia, Times New Roman, serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Georgia, Times New Roman, serif;&quot;&gt;Going back a few months, I see myself in a new institution, a completely new setting. We were freshly dispatched from different factories and were brought to this sorting facility, so that we could be sieved according to our merit and packed off to universities. We are expected to choose among the same old trodden paths (the careers where one is expected to earn the most).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Georgia, Times New Roman, serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Georgia, Times New Roman, serif;&quot;&gt;The first few days of my college were very inert. The entry was even worse: I came in 15 minutes late to my first class and was told that I was too early for the next! I had introduced myself to the lecturer in English and some of my classmates had come to the conclusion that I knew neither Kannada nor Hindi nor Marathi (as a matter of fact, I haven't learnt to speak Marathi yet).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Georgia, Times New Roman, serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Georgia, Times New Roman, serif;&quot;&gt;Having been in Hubli for the last 5 years, and now joining a science institution in Belgaum, where you know none, is a bit bizarre but more of a boon. There is absolutely no chance for any of my old stories to creep up; whether good, bad or embarrassing! Having my choice of language annulled (I had opted for French&amp;nbsp;as a second language, but had to take up Hindi instead) and then having to write notes aimlessly in every class is a bit frustrating, but I feel it is better to adjust myself for the better, than try to change others altogether. So, I'm signing off this talk, hoping that I'll feel more comfortable in our college in the days to come.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Georgia, Times New Roman, serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Georgia, Times New Roman, serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Georgia, Times New Roman, serif;&quot;&gt;P.S.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Georgia, Times New Roman, serif;&quot;&gt;I had written this piece 8-9 months ago, and I'd more than agree now that I've adjusted well to the new place and made many new acquaintances and friends.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 16:04:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/humble-beginnings/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/humble-beginnings/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Decision</title>
        <description>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Two days ago, a score of 600 in writing on the SAT shattered my false impression that my English writing was perspicuous, cogent and nothing short of brilliant. (I guess, being an introvert has its downsides too; it robbed me of my vital skills of expression.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The dams have cracked; more and more confusion has started to seep in. What to do? What not to do? I've begun over-thinking things; planning for tomorrow, for the next week, for the next month and what not. My thoughts are making the situation sound more serious than they actually are.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;But, yesterday, a pathway emerged in the form of my biology instructor's words. His digressions on working hard seemed to ring a bell, inspiring me to keep working until some more doors open up. So here I am today, with a decision to try the philosophy of working hard and hoping for the best, in short, a decision to try harder at being an optimist.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 22:35:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/perspective/a-decision/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/perspective/a-decision/</guid>
      </item>
    

  </channel>
</rss>
